(INTRIGUING
WESTERN MUSIC PLAYING)
（有趣的
西洋音乐演奏）
(MUSIC CRESCENDOES, FADES)
（音乐渐强、渐弱）
(MUSIC PULSES)
（音乐脉冲）
(SAILORS SPEAKING GERMAN)
（水手们讲德语）
(CAPTAIN IN GERMAN)
（船长用德语）
MAN: (IN ENGLISH) Uh, Sweden.
男士：（用英语）呃，瑞典。
(IN GERMAN)
（在德国）
MAN: (IN ENGLISH)
I'm... I'm... Swedish
男：（英语）
我是...我是...瑞典人
but I speak a little English.
但我会说一点英语。
We're coming on board.
我们要上船了。
(SAILORS SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
（水手们用德语喊叫）
(CAPTAIN ORDERING IN GERMAN)
（船长用德语点菜）
(IN ENGLISH) All are welcome.
All are welcome.
（英语）欢迎大家。
欢迎大家。
Even the little one.
He can come too.
即使是小个子。
他也可以来。
Welcome.
欢迎。
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
（悬疑的音乐播放）
Why are you here?
你为什么在这？
Just a little sailing holiday.
只是一个小小的航海假期。
A jolly boys trip.
一次快乐的男孩之旅。
Take your hands off.
把你的手拿开。
Papers?
文件？
Passport?
护照？
(GRUNTS) Here you go.
（咕噜声）给你。
Any other people on the boat?
船上还有其他人吗？
Just the two of us.
只有我们俩。
(IN GERMAN)
（在德国）
Nein.
不。
(CAPTAIN SPEAKING)
（船长讲话）
(IN ENGLISH) Come, come,
we have lots to eat...
（英语）来来来，
我们有很多吃的...
Take your dirty hands off me!
把你的脏手拿开！
- (SAILORS SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
- (GUNS COCKING)
-（水手们用德语喊叫）
-（枪待发）
CAPTAIN: (IN ENGLISH) Back off!
船长：（用英语）退后！
And you,
你呢，
put your hands in the air!
把你的手举到空中！
(LAUGHING)
（笑）
Ooh! (LAUGHING)
哦！ （笑）
You're in trouble now!
你现在有麻烦了！
You've been a naughty boy!
你本来就是个顽皮的孩子！
I'll give you 100 francs
to shoot him.
我给你100法郎
射杀他。
Don't shoot me!
别开枪打我！
(BOTH CONTINUE LAUGHING)
（两人都继续笑）
He hates Germans.
You should really shoot him.
他讨厌德国人。
你真的应该开枪打死他。
I... I'm sorry.
You are very scary.
我……对不起。
你很可怕。
MAN: Make him walk the plank.
男人：让他走木板。
He loves wood.
他喜欢木头。
(BOTH CONTINUE LAUGHING)
（两人都继续笑）
Dirty drunken animal!
肮脏的喝醉的动物！
Guilty as charged.
被指控有罪。
(BOTH LAUGHING)
（两人都笑）
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
（德语）
- (SAILORS SPEAKING GERMAN)
- (DRAWER RATTLES)
- （水手们说德语）
-（抽屉嘎嘎声）
(IN ENGLISH) I always take
a can of kerosene
（英语）我总是采取
一罐煤油
for just
these sort of occasions.
只是为了
这些场合。
(INHALES)
（吸气）
It's been a while,
有一阵子了，
but the last time
someone laughed at me
但最后一次
有人嘲笑我
when I boarded their vessel,
当我登上他们的船时
I gave them the choice.
我给了他们选择。
Either swim to shore
要么游到岸边
or take their chances
on a burning ship.
或者抓住机会
在一艘燃烧的船上。
(LIQUID POURING)
（液体浇注）
Hans and I wondered
which option they'd choose,
汉斯和我想知道
他们会选择哪个选项，
death by water or death by fire.
水死或火死。
Oddly, they chose both.
奇怪的是，他们都选择了。
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
（德语）
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC CONTINUES)
（悬疑音乐继续）
(IN ENGLISH) They waited
until the very last moment,
（英语）他们等待着
直到最后一刻，
until their hair was on fire,
直到头发着火，
and their blistered skin
peeled from their fingers,
和他们起泡的皮肤
从他们的手指上剥落，
before they immersed
themselves in water
在他们沉浸之前
自己在水中
in the vain hope
在徒劳的希望中
of reaching shore.
到达岸边。
One of them
其中之一
sank immediately and perished.
立即沉没并灭亡。
But to our amazement,
the big one,
但令我们惊讶的是，
大的那个，
he showed great spirit.
他表现出了伟大的精神。
In spite of all the odds...
尽管困难重重......
(IN GERMAN)
（在德国）
...he painstakingly
made it to shore.
...他煞费苦心
成功到达岸边。
We followed and cheered him on
我们跟着他并为他加油
and rewarded
this impressive achievement
并得到奖励
这一令人印象深刻的成就
with a bullet
用子弹
to the back of his head.
到他的后脑勺。
Isn't that funny?
这不是很有趣吗？
Why aren't you laughing?
你为什么不笑？
- (GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
- (SAILORS GRUNT, SCREAM)
-（枪声安静）
-（水手们咕哝、尖叫）
(SAILORS CLAMORING)
（水手们大声叫嚷）
- (SLASHING)
- (GASPS)
-（猛击）
-（喘气）
(AMUSING WESTERN MUSIC PLAYING)
（有趣的西方音乐演奏）
- (MAN GRUNTS)
- (GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
-（男人咕哝）
-（枪声安静）
- (GRUNTS)
- (SAILOR 1 SHOUTS IN GERMAN)
-（咕噜声）
- （水手 1 用德语喊叫）
- (GUN FIRES QUIETLY)
- (SAILOR 2 YELPS)
-（枪声安静）
-（水手 2 尖叫）
- (SAILOR 3 GRUNTS)
- (SAILORS SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
-（水手 3 咕噜声）
-（水手们用德语喊叫）
(SAILOR 4 SCREAMS)
（水手 4 尖叫）
- (GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
- (SAILORS GRUNTING)
-（枪声安静）
-（水手们咕哝着）
- (GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
- (SAILOR 5 GASPS)
-（枪声安静）
-（水手 5 喘息）
- (SIGHS)
- (SAILOR 6 YELPS)
-（叹气）
-（水手 6 尖叫）
(GROANING)
（呻吟）
- (GROWLS)
- (SAILOR 7 GROANS)
-（咆哮）
-（水手 7 呻吟）
(AMUSING
WESTERN MUSIC CONTINUES)
（有趣
西方音乐继续）
Nice work, Lassen.
干得好，拉森。
There's more
where that came from.
还有更多
那是从哪里来的。
Yes.
是的。
(LASSEN GROANS)
（拉森呻吟声）
(LASSEN GRUNTS)
（拉森咕哝）
Ah...
啊...
Not sure it's working, Lassen.
不确定它是否有效，拉森。
The captain
looks rather agitated.
船长
看起来比较激动。
They're bringing their guns
to bear.
他们带着枪
忍受忍受。
(MISSILE FIRES)
（导弹发射）
They'll find their range
soon, sir.
他们会找到自己的范围
很快，先生。
Freddy, should we be worried?
弗雷迪，我们应该担心吗？
Oh, I don't think so, sir.
哦，我不这么认为，先生。
It's a rather large explosive,
so I set a rather large fuse.
这是一个相当大的炸药
所以我设置了一个相当大的保险丝。
I located the outside
of the powder room,
我找到了外面
化妆间的，
so when it goes bang,
所以当它爆炸时
it really should go bang.
它真的应该爆炸。
(MISSILE FIRES)
（导弹发射）
(EXPLOSION)
（爆炸）
Closer...
靠近一点...
Should be any second now, chaps.
现在应该是任何时候了，伙计们。
(SAILORS CLAMORING IN DISTANCE)
（水手们在远处喊叫）
Freddy?
弗雷迪？
(EXPLOSION BOOMING)
（爆炸声）
Good work, Frederick.
干得好，弗雷德里克。
Thank you, Captain.
谢谢你，船长。
Now, any chance you can tell us
现在，只要有机会你可以告诉我们
what we're doing here, sir?
我们在这里做什么，先生？
(MUSIC FADES)
（音乐渐弱）
(PROJECTOR CLICKING)
（投影仪点击）
(JOLLY ORCHESTRAL MUSIC PLAYING)
（欢快的管弦乐演奏）
NEWSREADER: (ON PROJECTOR)
The war in Europe rages on
新闻播音员：（在投影仪上）
欧洲战争愈演愈烈
as Hitler and his Nazi horde
sweep aside all in their path.
作为希特勒和他的纳粹部落
扫除他们路上的一切。
Poland, Belgium and now France
波兰、比利时，现在是法国
have all fallen
to Hitler's fascist regime,
都倒下了
希特勒的法西斯政权，
leaving Britain
holding up the final hopes
离开英国
抱着最后的希望
of liberation
for all of Europe.
解放
对于整个欧洲。
So, come on, Blighty,
get ready for a fighty.
所以，来吧，布莱蒂，
准备好战斗吧。
But we cannot do it alone.
但我们无法单独做到这一点。
And any hope
for our American brothers
还有任何希望
为了我们的美国兄弟
to join us
from across the Atlantic
加入我们
来自大西洋彼岸
remains frustrated
仍然沮丧
by Germany's secret weapon,
the U-boat.
德国的秘密武器，
U型潜艇。
These deadly little submarines
这些致命的小型潜艇
hunt at will
in the North Atlantic.
随意狩猎
在北大西洋。
Undetectable, the U-boat
sinks ships indiscriminately,
不可探测，U 型潜艇
不分青红皂白地击沉船只，
whether carrying
munitions, provisions
是否携带
弹药、给养
or civilians heading
或平民前往
from our companions
across the pond.
来自我们的同伴
穿过池塘。
So long as the U-boats
rule the Atlantic,
只要有潜艇
统治大西洋，
it remains impossible
这仍然是不可能的
for America's brave troops
to reach our shores.
为了美国勇敢的军队
到达我们的海岸。
Will Britain be forced
to appease Hitler's plans
英国会被迫吗
安抚希特勒的计划
or face devastation
from his offensive?
否则将面临毁灭
从他的进攻中？
London burns
and her seas run red,
伦敦燃烧
她的海洋变成红色，
as bombs from above
and torpedoes from below
如来自上方的炸弹
和来自下方的鱼雷
grind the Brits down.
碾压英国人。
And with no defense
against these lethal U-boats,
并且没有防御
对抗这些致命的潜艇，
it appears all hope may be lost
看来所有的希望都破灭了
for peace in Europe.
为了欧洲的和平。
- (MUSIC STOPS)
- (PROJECTOR CLICKS)
-（音乐停止）
-（投影仪点击声）
The Germans cut off
our supply chain with U-boats,
德国人切断了
我们的潜艇供应链，
we cut off the supply chain
to the U-boats.
我们切断供应链
到U型潜艇。
Through our intelligence agents,
通过我们的情报人员，
we've found a way.
我们找到了办法。
(INTRIGUING WESTERN
MUSIC PLAYING)
（有趣的西部片
音乐播放）
The entire
整个
servicing, repairing,
and rearming
保养、修理、
并重新武装
of Hitler's
Atlantic U-boat fleet...
希特勒的
大西洋U型潜艇舰队...
is operated
by two Nazi tug boats...
已运行
由两艘纳粹拖船......
and an Italian supply ship
in Fernando Po.
和一艘意大利补给船
在费尔南多·波。
I need men who are willing
to go and sink those ships.
我需要愿意的男人
去击沉那些船。
Why don't we just
air-raid Fernando Po
我们为什么不直接
空袭费尔南多·波
and sink the ships?
并击沉船只？
(EXHALES)
（呼气）
Because crafty Germans,
being crafty Germans,
因为狡猾的德国人，
作为狡猾的德国人，
have positioned themselves
in a Spanish colony.
已经给自己定位了
在西班牙殖民地。
Fernando Po
is neutral territory.
费尔南多·波
是中立领土。
If we attack that colony,
如果我们攻击那个殖民地，
the rest of unoccupied Europe
will join the Nazis,
欧洲其他未占领地区
将加入纳粹，
and it's only
a question of time
而且这只是
时间问题
before we find ourselves
在我们找到自己之前
frying big pink sausages
煎大粉红香肠
wearing nothing but lederhosen.
只穿皮短裤。
Hitler is not
playing by the rules
希特勒不是
遵守游戏规则
and neither are we.
我们也不是。
This will of course be
an unsanctioned,
这当然会是
未经批准的、
unauthorized
and unofficial mission.
未经授权的
和非官方任务。
If they're captured
by the British,
如果他们被抓获
由英国人，
they'll be thrown in jail.
他们将被投入监狱。
But if the Nazis find them...
但如果纳粹找到他们...
it's torture and death.
这是酷刑和死亡。
MAN: Somewhat contentiously,
男士：有点争议，
I may have just the man,
我可能只有这个男人，
but rather inconveniently,
但相当不方便，
he's currently incarcerated
at His Majesty's pleasure.
他目前被监禁
遵照陛下的意愿。
We may not like his attitude,
我们可能不喜欢他的态度，
but he's bold, he's a killer,
但他很大胆，他是个杀手
and the men
will follow him anywhere.
和男人们
会跟随他到任何地方。
Are we sure this is a good idea?
我们确定这是个好主意吗？
Of course we're not.
我们当然不是。
But we're desperate.
但我们很绝望。
- Send him in.
- (DOOR OPENS)
- 把他送进来。
-（门打开）
SERGEANT: Forward!
中士：前进！
- (FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
- (CHAINS CLINKING)
-（脚步声接近）
-（链条叮当响）
SERGEANT: Stand there, Major.
中士：站在那里，少校。
(INTRIGUING MUSIC CONTINUES)
（有趣的音乐继续）
MAN: Thank you, Sergeant.
男：谢谢你，中士。
Gus March-Phillips,
格斯·马奇-菲利普斯，
this is Lieutenant Commander...
这是中尉……
Fleming. Ian Fleming.
弗莱明.伊恩·弗莱明.
He used to be
at Naval Intelligence,
他以前是
在海军情报局，
now he works for me.
现在他为我工作。
Why am I here, M?
我为什么在这里，M？
I have a mission
I want you to lead.
我有一个使命
我要你来领导。
Why are you asking me, M?
你为什么问我，M？
Help yourself
to a cup of tea, Major.
帮助自己
喝杯茶，少校。
(GUS CLEARS THROAT)
（格斯清嗓子）
We both know that I'm...
我们都知道我是...
not very popular
with the administration.
不太受欢迎
与行政部门。
M: The reason
they find you unattractive
甲：原因
他们发现你没有吸引力
is the very reason
I find you attractive.
就是这个原因
我发现你很有魅力。
Mission?
使命？
M: Operation Postmaster.
M：邮政局长行动。
To neutralize the German U-boats
压制德国潜艇
in the North Atlantic.
在北大西洋。
(RATTLING)
（嘎嘎作响）
- And, uh, what's the plan?
- (SIGHS)
- 那么，呃，计划是什么？
-（叹气）
FLEMING: The U-boats need
弗莱明：U型潜艇需要
- fuel and torpedoes.
- Oh.
- 燃料和鱼雷。
- 哦。
But they also need
但他们也需要
carbon dioxide filters
for oxygen.
二氧化碳过滤器
用于氧气。
Without them, they can't dive
and they can't hunt.
没有他们，他们就无法潜水
他们不能打猎。
Stuck on the surface,
they're obsolete.
粘在表面，
它们已经过时了。
Target?
目标？
The Duchessa d'Aosta.
奥斯塔公爵夫人。
She's an Italian ship
the Germans have been using...
她是一艘意大利船
德国人一直在使用...
(CONTINUES DRAGGING CHAIR)
（继续拖着椅子）
(FLEMING CLEARS THROAT)
（弗莱明清嗓子）
...to refuel,
re-arm and replenish
...加油，
重新武装并补充
the CO2 filters
for the entire fleet.
二氧化碳过滤器
对于整个舰队。
She's hidden
off the coast of West Africa.
她隐藏了
西非海岸附近。
A small island
called Fernando Po.
一个小岛
名叫费尔南多·波。
We want you to, um, sink her.
我们希望你，嗯，击沉她。
M: You'll be posing as fishermen
M：你会假扮成渔民
sailing down the west coast
沿着西海岸航行
on board a trawler
loaded with enough explosives
在拖网渔船上
装有足够的炸药
to destroy the Duchessa.
摧毁公爵夫人。
This is Agents
Heron and Stewart.
这是特工
海伦和斯图尔特。
They'll be working
undercover on the island.
他们将会工作
岛上的卧底。
Mr. Heron's
already established there,
海伦先生的
那里已经设立了，
running various businesses.
经营各种业务。
What businesses?
哪些业务？
A casino bar,
and illegal exports game.
赌场酒吧，
和非法出口游戏。
Profitable?
有利可图？
- I do quite well.
- (LIGHTER CLICKS)
- 我做得很好。
-（轻击声）
High-ranking Nazis
are my most valued clients.
纳粹高层
是我最尊贵的客户。
Good for you.
对你有好处。
(LIGHTER CLICKS)
（轻击声）
M: Miss Stewart,
an actress and singer,
男：斯图尔特小姐，
演员和歌手，
has been training with us
for the last two years.
一直在和我们一起训练
过去两年。
She'll be posing
她会摆出姿势
as a gold trader from New York.
作为一名来自纽约的黄金交易员。
Her mission is
to seduce and distract
她的使命是
引诱和分散注意力
the island's Commanding
Officer Heinrich Luhr.
岛上的指挥
海因里希·鲁尔警官。
She's very capable
and somewhat motivated.
她非常有能力
并且有些动力。
Motivated how, sir?
先生，怎么激励？
My mother's side
were German Jews.
我妈妈的身边
是德国犹太人。
They were the first to go.
他们是最先走的。
Very sorry to hear that.
听到这个消息我感到非常遗憾。
I'm sure you'll recover.
我相信你会康复的。
M: We have 44 days
男：我们还有44天
before the Nazis
move their operation.
在纳粹之前
移动他们的操作。
We won't find them again.
我们不会再找到他们了。
If I'm to do this,
I'll need my own team.
如果我要做这件事
我需要我自己的团队。
You won't like them.
They're all, uh...
你不会喜欢他们的。
他们都是，呃…
mad.
疯狂的。
They'll need to be.
Give us their names.
他们需要这样。
请告诉我们他们的名字。
Henry Hayes.
亨利·海斯。
A smart, young Irishman
who hates the Nazis
一个聪明的年轻爱尔兰人
谁讨厌纳粹
because his older brother,
因为他的哥哥，
who was a close friend of mine,
他是我的密友，
drowned after a U-boat
sank his fishing trawler.
在潜艇追击后溺水身亡
击沉了他的拖网渔船。
I've taken him under my wing
ever since.
我把他置于我的羽翼之下
从那时起。
He's cunning, quiet and wily.
他狡猾、安静、狡猾。
More to the point,
更重要的是，
Hayes is a magnificent sailor
and I trust him.
海耶斯是一位出色的水手
我相信他。
If we're going
to try and sink a large ship,
如果我们要去的话
试图击沉一艘大船
we'll need
Freddy "The Buzz" frogman.
我们需要
“嗡嗡声”弗雷迪蛙人。
He can swim across the channel
with his feet tied together.
他可以游过海峡
他的脚被绑在一起。
Admittedly,
诚然，
he's a convicted arsonist
and a terrible misery
他是一名被定罪的纵火犯
和可怕的痛苦
unless he's destroying something.
除非他正在毁掉什么东西。
But he's very good
at blowing things up.
但他很好
炸毁东西。
Next, we'll need
the Danish hammer.
接下来，我们需要
丹麦锤子。
Anders Lassen.
安德斯·拉森。
Grew up wrestling bears
长大的摔跤熊
and hunting elk
on his family estate.
和狩猎麋鹿
在他的家族庄园里。
He's a legend
他是一个传奇
with a Bowie knife
and a bow and arrow.
用鲍伊刀
还有弓和箭。
He ran away at 18
to fight the Nazis
他18岁时就逃跑了
对抗纳粹
after the Gestapo tortured
his brother to death.
在盖世太保遭受酷刑之后
他的兄弟死了。
He gave up filleting game
for gutting Nazis.
他放弃了切片游戏
为了消灭纳粹。
He then turned up on our shores
然后他出现在我们的海岸上
ready to fight alongside us.
准备好与我们并肩作战。
He is an uncontrollable mad dog
他是一只无法控制的疯狗
who knows
a hundred creative ways
谁知道
一百种创意方法
to kill a man.
去杀一个人。
And finally,
最后，
and most importantly,
we'll need Geoffrey Appleyard.
最重要的是，
我们需要杰弗里·阿普尔亚德。
Yes, we thought you might.
是的，我们认为你可能会。
That's why we sent him
这就是为什么我们派他来
on a reconnaissance mission
to Fernando Po.
执行侦察任务
费尔南多·波。
Unfortunately,
很遗憾，
the Nazis nabbed him
on his return.
纳粹抓住了他
在他回来时。
All the more reason.
He knows what we need to know.
更何况还有理由。
他知道我们需要知道什么。
He's a master planner,
他是一位总体规划师
a master survivor,
a chess grand master
一位幸存者大师，
国际象棋大师
and a surgeon with the blade.
和一个拿着刀片的外科医生。
We spent two weeks together
in a Dunkirk foxhole
我们一起度过了两周
在敦刻尔克散兵坑里
and if it wasn't for Apple,
I would still be there today.
如果不是苹果，
今天我仍然会在那里。
No Apple, no mission.
没有苹果，就没有使命。
I'm afraid that's impossible.
恐怕这是不可能的。
Why?
为什么？
M: Because he's being held
M：因为他被拘留了
by an entire German garrison
on La Palma.
整个德国驻军
在拉帕尔马岛。
(HUFFS, LAUGHS)
（生气，笑）
La Palma's on the way.
拉帕尔马正在路上。
(MARJORIE SCOFFS)
（玛乔丽·嘲笑）
- That's insanity.
- You let me worry about that.
- 这太疯狂了。
- 你让我担心这个。
I must get me
one of those coats.
我必须得到我
其中一件外套。
(AMUSING WESTERN MUSIC PLAYING)
（有趣的西方音乐演奏）
(LAUGHING)
（笑）
Now, any chance you can tell us
现在，只要有机会你可以告诉我们
what we're doing here, sir?
我们在这里做什么，先生？
Dry yourself off, frogman,
and I'll tell you.
擦干身子吧，蛙人，
我会告诉你。
The curiosity is
eating us all up, sir.
好奇心是
把我们都吃掉了，先生。
GUS: I apologize
for all the secrecy, chaps.
GUS：我道歉
为了所有的秘密，伙计们。
But this is
但这是
an unsanctioned, unofficial
and unauthorized mission.
未经批准的、非官方的
和未经授权的任务。
If we're picked up by the Brits,
如果我们被英国人抓住
we will all go to jail.
我们都会进监狱。
If we're picked up
by the Germans,
如果我们被接走
由德国人，
torture and death.
酷刑和死亡。
So, it's just
the four of us then?
所以，这只是
那么我们四个人呢？
And Captain Appleyard.
还有阿普尔亚德船长。
He's responsible
for securing this information.
他有责任
为了保护这些信息。
He is, however,
in a spot of bother.
然而他却是
在一个麻烦的地方。
He is being held
by the Germans on La Palma.
他被关押
德国人在拉帕尔马岛上。
Our first job
is to liberate him.
我们的第一份工作
就是要解放他。
- Oh, so, that's all, is it?
- GUS: No.
- 哦，所以，就这些了，是吗？
- 格斯：没有。
We need to confirm
Appleyard's intelligence.
我们需要确认
阿普尔亚德的智慧。
That's why
there are two more agents
这就是为什么
还有两个代理
on their way to Fernando Po
by train, as we speak.
前往费尔南多波的路上
正如我们所说，乘火车。
Doing what, exactly?
到底在做什么？
They'll be ensuring
他们将确保
that those ships
are filled with supplies,
那些船
都装满了物资，
so they're worth blowing up
in the first place.
所以它们值得炸毁
首先。
(TRAIN HORN BLARING)
（火车喇叭鸣响）
MARJORIE: It's one thing
taking over the world,
玛乔丽：这是一回事
接管世界，
but do they have to
take over the kitchen too?
但他们必须这样做吗
也接管厨房？
It's all sausage,
cabbage and black bread.
都是香肠啊
卷心菜和黑面包。
HERON: Who would
you have preferred?
海伦：谁会
你有首选吗？
MARJORIE: The French offer
the refined classical take.
MARJORIE：法国的提议
精致的古典风格。
Cote de boeuf,
fromage, le beurre...
牛坡，
奶酪、le beurre...
- ca suffit!
- (MEN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
- 够了！
- （男人说话含糊不清）
What about the rustic
spontaneity of the Italians?
田园风又怎样呢
意大利人的自发性？
Their oils, the linguine,
the tomatoes.
他们的油、扁面条、
西红柿。
I'd climb over the linguine
to get to the fettucine.
我会爬过扁面条
去吃宽面条。
But the cinghiale.
但辛吉亚莱。
MARJORIE: Mmm.
玛乔丽：嗯。
You have me with the wild boar.
你让我和野猪在一起。
But then again,
the Spanish offer
但话又说回来，
西班牙报价
the smorgasbord
自助餐
of the regional paella
and tapas.
地区海鲜饭
和小吃。
And Jamon Iberico Andalucia.
还有安达卢西亚伊比利亚火腿。
So?
所以？
We're between
a rock and a hard place.
我们之间
岩石和坚硬的地方。
If the Brits win the war,
如果英国人赢得战争
we're stuck with fish and chips.
我们被炸鱼和薯条困住了。
If the Germans win the war,
如果德国人赢得战争
we're stuck with this menu.
我们被这个菜单困住了。
So?
所以？
We'll have the sausage,
the cabbage
我们要香肠，
卷心菜
- and the black bread please.
- (SIGHS)
-还有黑面包。
-（叹气）
Tres bien. Merci.
非常好。谢谢。
(SOLDIERS LAUGHING,
SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
（士兵们笑，
说话含糊不清）
(EXHALES)
（呼气）
Our situation?
我们的情况？
Steady.
稳定的。
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATION)
（含糊不清的对话）
(EXCITING MUSIC PLAYING)
（激动人心的音乐演奏）
Steady.
稳定的。
(EXHALES)
（呼气）
Now.
现在。
(SOLDIERS SPEAKING GERMAN
INDISTINCTLY, LAUGHING)
（士兵们讲德语
含糊其辞，笑）
(IN GERMAN)
（在德国）
MARJORIE: Mmm.
玛乔丽：嗯。
(IN ENGLISH) I'm exhausted.
（英语）我累坏了。
(IN GERMAN)
（在德国）
- (LAUGHING STOPS)
- (MUSIC FADES)
-（笑声停止）
-（音乐渐弱）
- (CHUCKLES)
- (SOLDIERS SHUSHING)
-（轻笑）
-（士兵们嘘声）
(GULPS)
（吞咽）
Entschuldigung, bitte.
Entschuldigung，bitte。
(EXCITING MUSIC PLAYING)
（激动人心的音乐演奏）
(SOLDIERS SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
（士兵们含糊其辞）
OFFICER: (IN ENGLISH) Halt!
警官：（用英语）停下来！
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
（悬疑的音乐播放）
(CHATTER STOPS)
（闲聊停止）
(IN GERMAN)
（在德国）
(IN ENGLISH) Is there a problem?
（英语）有问题吗？
(IN GERMAN)
（在德国）
(IN ENGLISH) I can manage
myself, thank you.
（英语）我可以应付
我自己，谢谢。
(IN GERMAN)
（在德国）
(IN ENGLISH)
Allow me, Miss Stewart.
（用英语讲）
请允许我，斯图尔特小姐。
(MUSIC FADES)
（音乐渐弱）
(IN GERMAN)
（在德国）
(IN ENGLISH) Allow me.
（英语）请允许我。
Thank you.
谢谢。
(EXCITING MUSIC PLAYING)
（激动人心的音乐演奏）
SOLDIER: Prost!
士兵：普罗斯特！
(SOLDIERS SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
（士兵们含糊其辞）
(EXCITING MUSIC CONTINUES)
（激动人心的音乐继续）
HERON: Door.
海伦：门。
Locked.
锁定。
HERON: Case?
海伦：案子？
Working on it.
正在努力。
(UNLOCKS CASE)
（解锁箱子）
(SOLDIERS SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
（士兵们含糊其辞）
(DIAL CLICKING)
（拨号盘点击）
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
（电话铃声）
(SIGNAL BEEPING)
（信号蜂鸣声）
OPERATOR: Sir, contact.
接线员：先生，请联系。
- (SIGNAL BEEPING)
- Contact.
-（信号蜂鸣声）
- 接触。
Standing by.
站在。
MARJORIE:
Duchessa's manifest. Ready?
玛乔丽：
公爵夫人的清单。准备好？
- Ready.
- 400 B-grade torpedoes. Check.
- 准备好。
- 400枚B级鱼雷。查看。
(EXCITING MUSIC PLAYING)
（激动人心的音乐演奏）
(SIGNAL BEEPING)
（信号蜂鸣声）
OPERATOR: 400 B-grade torpedoes.
操作员：400 枚 B 级鱼雷。
M: Check.
男：检查一下。
Check.
查看。
MARJORIE:
5,000 tons of diesel. Check.
玛乔丽：
柴油5000吨。查看。
(CLICKING)
（点击）
(SIGNAL BEEPING)
（信号蜂鸣声）
OPERATOR: 5,000 tons of diesel.
运营商：5000吨柴油。
- Lieutenant.
- OPERATOR: Yes, sir?
- 中尉。
- 接线员：是吗，先生？
M: Check.
男：检查一下。
- (SIGNAL BEEPING)
- HERON: Check.
-（信号蜂鸣声）
- HERON：检查。
10,000 carbon dioxide filters.
Check.
10,000 个二氧化碳过滤器。
查看。
(SOLDIERS SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
（士兵们含糊其辞）
End of message from Stork, sir.
鹳鸟的消息结束了，先生。
Confirm receipt.
确认收据。
(SIGNAL BEEPING)
（信号蜂鸣声）
HERON: Receipt confirmed.
HERON：收据已确认。
Urgent, Chequers.
紧急，支票。
Get the car ready.
Inform Fleming.
准备好车。
通知弗莱明。
Let's pack it up.
我们把它打包吧。
No point robbing the bank
抢银行没有意义
if there's no gold in the vault.
如果金库里没有黄金。
(EXCITING MUSIC CONTINUES)
（激动人心的音乐继续）
(SOLDIERS CONVERSING, LAUGHING)
（士兵们交谈，大笑）
Thank you.
谢谢。
It's truly comforting to know
知道这真是令人欣慰
there's at least one gentleman
in the world.
至少有一位绅士
在世界上。
SOLDIER: Ah! (SPEAKING GERMAN)
Idiot!
士兵：啊！ （德语）
笨蛋！
(HERON, IN GERMAN)
（苍鹭，德语）
(IN ENGLISH) Good day.
（英语）美好的一天。
(MUSIC FADES)
（音乐渐弱）
Sausage, cabbage
and black bread.
香肠、卷心菜
和黑面包。
(SIGHS)
（叹气）
MAN: Hitler
has made us an offer.
男：希特勒
已向我们发出报价。
An appeasement.
绥靖政策。
But we must step down our army,
但我们必须撤军，
surrender our Navy
and accept Nazi rule.
投降我们的海军
并接受纳粹统治。
Otherwise, he promises
否则，他保证
total destruction of Britain
and her empire.
英国的彻底毁灭
和她的帝国。
Our best option
我们最好的选择
is to take Hitler's deal
while we can.
就是接受希特勒的交易
当我们可以的时候。
The Air Marshal agrees.
空军元帅对此表示同意。
He has more bombs,
more men, more machines.
他还有更多的炸弹
更多的人，更多的机器。
We won't survive much longer.
我们活不了多久了。
You have to make
the only decision you can make
你必须做
你能做出的唯一决定
in good conscience,
Prime Minister.
凭良心来说，
总理。
CHURCHILL: Good God, girls.
Listen to yourselves.
丘吉尔：天哪，姑娘们。
听听你自己的声音。
It's not appeasement,
it's surrender.
这不是绥靖政策，
这是投降。
You still fail to realize
who we're up against.
你还是没有意识到
我们的对手是谁。
With respect, Prime Minister,
it's you who doesn't realize.
尊敬的总理，
是你没有意识到。
We cannot hope to defeat him.
我们不能指望打败他。
Hitler is
the mainspring of evil,
希特勒是
罪恶的主要源泉，
a guttersnipe.
阴沟鸟。
This is not a man
that we can negotiate with.
这不是一个男人
我们可以与之谈判。
I've read his book,
Admiral Pound.
我读过他的书
庞德海军上将。
The man is a vicious,
victimized ideologue.
男人是个恶毒的人，
受害的意识形态。
He cannot be trusted.
他不值得信任。
If I thought that
we could've achieved peace
如果我这么想的话
我们本可以实现和平
through surrendering,
通过投降，
I'd have done it already.
我早就这么做了。
We need to stop our country
from starving.
我们需要阻止我们的国家
免于饥饿。
We need
three million tons of supplies
我们需要
300万吨物资
to cross the Atlantic
every month.
横渡大西洋
每个月。
We are currently losing
50% of that to U-boat attacks.
我们目前正在失去
其中 50% 是 U 艇攻击。
Another reason to take the deal.
接受这笔交易的另一个原因。
I've not finished,
Algernon, darling.
我还没说完，
阿尔吉侬，亲爱的。
We need the Americans,
我们需要美国人
and they will
never enter the war
他们会的
永远不要参战
if we already appear
to be a losing side.
如果我们已经出现
成为失败的一方。
Ending hostilities with Germany
结束与德国的敌对行动
is the best path
out of this mess.
是最好的路径
摆脱这个混乱。
We are all in agreement,
Prime Minister.
我们都一致同意，
总理。
Thank you, gentlemen.
谢谢你们，先生们。
(STERNLY) Yes,
thank you, gentlemen!
（严肃地）是的，
谢谢你们，先生们！
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
（悬疑的音乐播放）
(DOOR OPENS)
（门打开）
CHURCHILL: M, Fleming,
this better be good news.
丘吉尔：弗莱明先生，
这最好是个好消息。
M: Prime Minister,
M：总理，
we have the manifest here, sir.
我们这里有清单，先生。
It's been confirmed
已确认
the Duchessa
is fully laden with supplies
公爵夫人
装满了物资
to keep the U-boats
operational indefinitely.
保留U型潜艇
无限期运行。
If we're going to sink her,
now is the time.
如果我们要把她沉没
现在是时候了。
They're on their way.
他们正在路上。
And their chances?
他们的机会呢？
Well, if anyone can, they can.
好吧，如果有人可以，他们就可以。
But if we're discovered,
但如果我们被发现了
parliament will remove you
from office.
议会将罢免你
从办公室。
Well,
出色地，
we'd better make sure
we're not discovered then.
我们最好确保
那时我们就没有被发现。
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC FADES)
（悬疑的音乐渐渐消失）
We'll take it
from the cliffside.
我们会接受它
从悬崖边。
It's an 85-foot sheer climb.
这是 85 英尺的陡坡。
No one should notice
没有人应该注意到
a small, innocuous
fishing vessel.
一个小的、无害的
渔船。
We'll set up in the woods
and see what we're up against,
我们将在树林里安营扎寨
看看我们面临着什么，
then we'll go for a night raid.
然后我们就去夜袭。
Slip in quietly,
find Apple, come out fast.
悄悄溜进去，
找到苹果，快点出来。
Numbers?
数字？
Intelligence suggests
a garrison of 50 to 60.
情报表明
驻军50至60人。
That should be about 15 each.
每个应该是15个左右。
Lassen, try not to be greedy.
You do have a reputation.
拉森，尽量不要贪心。
你确实有名气。
My killing days are over.
我杀戮的日子结束了。
I'm just here
as a peacekeeping observer.
我就在这里
作为维和观察员。
(MEN CHUCKLE)
（男人轻笑）
Freddy, bag the kit,
silence the weapons.
弗雷迪，把工具包装进袋子里，
让武器安静下来。
(EXCITING MUSIC PLAYING)
（激动人心的音乐演奏）
(SEAGULL SQUAWKING)
（海鸥的叫声）
(GUN COCKS)
（枪旋塞）
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
（戏剧性的音乐演奏）
(SOLDIERS SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
（士兵们用德语喊叫）
FREDDY: When do we go?
弗雷迪：我们什么时候走？
GUS: 0200.
格斯：0200。
Take the towers first,
then move onto the radio room,
先拿塔楼，
然后进入广播室，
barracks and end up
in the control room...
军营并结束
在控制室...
- (DOG BARKS IN THE DISTANCE)
- What do we have here?
-（远处有狗叫）
- 我们有什么在这里？
Gestapo.
盖世太保。
How'd you know?
你怎么知道的？
GUS: The badder they are,
the better they're dressed.
GUS：他们越糟糕，
他们穿得越好。
I really must get me
one of those coats.
我真的必须得到我
其中一件外套。
They must be here for Apple.
他们肯定是为了苹果而来。
It's either torture
or, uh, extraction, sir.
要么就是折磨
或者，呃，提取，先生。
GUS: If they extract him,
it'll be the end of Apple.
GUS：如果他们把他救出来
这将是苹果的终结。
We won't be seeing him again.
我们不会再见到他了。
I'm afraid, gentlemen,
恐怕先生们，
we're not going
to have the luxury of night.
我们不会去
享受奢华的夜晚。
We're going
to have to go in now.
本来打算
现在必须进去。
(SOLDIERS SPEAKING GERMAN)
（士兵们讲德语）
(BOTH SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
（两人都用德语喊叫）
- (ARROWS WHIZZING)
- (SOLDIERS GRUNT)
-（箭矢呼啸）
-（士兵咕噜声）
(SPLUTTERS)
（喋喋不休）
(MUSIC FADES)
（音乐渐弱）
(IN ENGLISH) So,
what's happened there then?
（英语）所以，
那儿发生了什么事？
It looks like
看起来像
they've been plugged
full of arrows, Haysey.
他们已经被堵住了
充满了箭，海西。
Well, where did the arrows go?
那么，箭头去哪儿了呢？
FREDDY: Straight through them.
弗雷迪：直接穿过他们。
(LASSEN GRUNTING)
（拉森咕噜声）
There were
two more round the other side.
有
另一边还有两个。
Where are they now?
他们现在在哪里？
Same place as these two.
和这两个是同一个地方。
Nazi heaven.
纳粹天堂。
Well, we've got
less than seven minutes
好吧，我们有
不到七分钟
before they're missed.
在他们被错过之前。
Alarms, dogs. None of it good.
警报，狗。没有一个是好的。
(GUNS FIRING)
（枪声响起）
Go undercover of the engine.
深入了解发动机。
Only break cover
when things go bang.
只能打破盖子
当事情发生的时候。
(SIGHS)
（叹气）
I have a great idea, Lassen.
我有一个好主意，拉森。
Why don't you march off
by yourself
你为何不出发
自己
and fill those Germans
full of arrows?
并填补那些德国人
充满了箭头？
(TENSE WESTERN MUSIC PLAYING)
（紧张的西方音乐演奏）
(GRUNTS)
（咕噜声）
GUS: Freddy, grab the scissors
and help him with that fence.
GUS：弗雷迪，拿起剪刀
并帮助他修好栅栏。
Aye, sir.
好的，先生。
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
（激动人心的音乐演奏）
(GRUNTS)
（咕噜声）
(SOLDIER SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
（士兵含糊其辞）
(VEHICLE ENGINE WHIRRING)
（车辆发动机嗡嗡作响）
Haysey, you're with me.
We go left.
海西，你和我在一起。
我们向左走。
Freddy, Lassen, you go right.
弗雷迪、拉森，你们往右走。
Fill your boots, gentlemen,
and bon appetit.
先生们，装满你的靴子，
祝你胃口好。
(SNIPPING)
（截图）
(ENGINE SPUTTERING)
（发动机溅射）
- See you at the tower.
- (GUNS COCK)
- 塔楼见。
-（枪旋塞）
GUS: And remember, gentlemen,
try to have fun.
GUS：请记住，先生们，
尝试玩得开心。
- (GUNS FIRING QUIETLY)
- (SOLDIERS CLAMORING)
-（枪声安静）
-（士兵们大声叫喊）
(ENGINE WHIRRING)
（发动机呼呼）
(OFFICER SPEAKING GERMAN)
（军官讲德语）
(MAN SPEAKING ON RADIO)
（男子在广播中讲话）
(GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
（枪声安静）
(ENGINE WHIRRING)
（发动机呼呼）
(GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
（枪声安静）
- (GROANS)
- (IN ENGLISH) So far, so good.
-（呻吟声）
-（英语）到目前为止，一切都很好。
- (ENGINE WHIRRING)
- Doing rather well, Haysey.
-（发动机呼呼声）
- 做得相当好，海西。
Oh, why thank you, sir.
噢，为什么要谢谢你，先生。
(SOLDIER SPEAKING GERMAN)
（士兵说德语）
(OFFICER SPEAKING GERMAN)
（军官讲德语）
(OFFICER 2 SPEAKING GERMAN)
（2 号官员说德语）
(SOLDIERS LAUGHING)
（士兵们笑）
(GUS LAUGHING UPROARIOUSLY)
（格斯哈哈大笑）
(STOPS LAUGHING)
（停止笑）
(IN ENGLISH) It's very good.
（英语）非常好。
- (GUNS FIRING QUIETLY)
- (SOLDIERS SCREAMING)
-（枪声安静）
-（士兵们尖叫）
(GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
（枪声安静）
(OFFICER 1 SPEAKING GERMAN)
（1 号官员说德语）
(OFFICER 2 SPEAKING GERMAN)
（2 号官员说德语）
(OFFICER 1 SPEAKING GERMAN)
（1 号官员说德语）
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
（德语）
- (OFFICER 3 SPEAKING GERMAN)
- (MUSIC CRESCENDOES, FADES)
- （警官 3 说德语）
-（音乐渐强、渐弱）
- (EXPLOSION)
- (SOLDIERS SCREAMING)
-（爆炸）
-（士兵们尖叫）
(ALL CLAMORING)
（所有人都在叫嚷）
(IN ENGLISH) Sounds like
stealth mode's over.
（英语）听起来像
隐身模式结束了
Haysey, down!
海西，下来！
(SOLDIERS SCREAMING)
（士兵们尖叫）
(BULLETS CLANGING)
（子弹叮当作响）
(MACHINE GUN STOPS)
（机枪停）
(ALARM BLARING)
（警报声响起）
(SOLDIERS CLAMORING OUTSIDE)
（士兵们在外面喊叫）
(UPBEAT
ELECTRONIC MUSIC PLAYING)
（乐观
电子音乐演奏）
- (GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
- (GROANS)
-（枪声安静）
-（呻吟声）
(COUGHING)
（咳嗽）
- (HACKS)
- (GUN FIRES QUIETLY)
-（黑客）
-（枪声安静）
(SOLDIERS COUGHING)
（士兵咳嗽）
(SOLDIERS SHOUT, GROAN)
（士兵们喊叫、呻吟）
(SOLDIER GROANS)
（士兵呻吟声）
(GUN FIRES QUIETLY)
（枪声安静）
- (SOLDIER GROANING)
- (GUN FIRES QUIETLY)
-（士兵呻吟）
-（枪声安静）
(SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
（用德语喊叫）
- (GUN FIRES QUIETLY)
- (GROANS)
-（枪声安静）
-（呻吟声）
(BOTH GRUNTING)
（两人都咕哝着）
(SOLDIERS CLAMORING)
（士兵们大声叫喊）
(GROANS)
（呻吟声）
- Nein! Nein! (GROANS)
- (GRUNTS)
- 不！不！（呻吟声）
-（咕噜声）
(WHIMPERS)
（呜咽声）
(BOTH GRUNT)
（两人咕噜声）
(CLAMORING, SCREAMING)
（吵闹、尖叫）
(BOTH GRUNTING)
（两人都咕哝着）
- (STABBING)
- (OFFICER GROANS)
-（刺伤）
-（军官呻吟）
- (LASSEN GRUNTS)
- (SOLDIER YELLS)
-（拉森咕哝）
-（士兵大喊）
(YELLING)
（大喊）
(LASSEN AND SOLDIER GRUNT)
（拉森和士兵咕噜声）
- (SOLDIER SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
- (GUN FIRES QUIETLY)
-（士兵用德语喊叫）
-（枪声安静）
(MUSIC FADES)
（音乐渐弱）
(LASSEN PANTING)
（拉森气喘吁吁）
(IN ENGLISH)
Do we know each other?
（用英语讲）
我们彼此认识吗？
- No.
- (SOLDIER CHOKING)
- 不。
-（士兵窒息）
(SPLUTTERING)
（溅射声）
(KNIFE CLINKS)
（刀子叮当响）
- (STAB)
- (STABS)
- (SOLDIER SCREAMS)
-（士兵尖叫声）
(CLEARS THROAT)
（清嗓子）
(LASSEN GRUNTS)
（拉森咕哝）
Is that a heart, Lassen?
那是一颗心吗，拉森？
For the avoidance of doubt.
为避免疑义。
Apple, old boy.
苹果，老男孩。
- Gus.
- GUS: I see you two have met.
- 格斯。
- GUS：我看你们两个已经见过面了。
This is Haysey.
这是海西。
- GEOFFREY: Pleasure, Haysey.
- Pleasure's mine.
- 杰弗里：很高兴，海西。
- 快乐是我的。
I thought you might need these.
我想你可能需要这些。
Jolly thoughtful of you.
真高兴为你着想。
FREDDY: You all find him?
弗雷迪：你们都找到他了吗？
Oh, goody.
哦，好极了。
Bloody hell,
what happened to your nipples?
该死的地狱，
你的乳头怎么了？
You all right?
你没事吧？
Couldn't unplug me, could you?
Battery's still on.
无法拔掉我的电源，可以吗？
电池还开着。
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
（电劈啪作响）
(INTRIGUING
WESTERN MUSIC PLAYING)
（有趣的
西洋音乐演奏）
(GUS LAUGHING)
（格斯笑）
(DRAMATIC GUITAR MUSIC PLAYING)
（戏剧性的吉他音乐演奏）
(MOTOR WHIRRING)
（电机呼呼）
(CROWD SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
（众人含糊其辞）
(GREETING IN ITALIAN)
（意大利语问候）
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
（模糊不清的喋喋不休）
(SOLDIERS GRUNT)
（士兵咕噜声）
(FOGHORN BLARES)
（雾号声）
(IN ENGLISH)
Did you see the Duchessa,
（用英语讲）
你看到公爵夫人了吗
the tug boats?
拖船？
And rather
a lot of Nazi soldiers.
相反
很多纳粹士兵。
Why wasn't that in your report?
为什么你的报告中没有这一点？
Because those soldiers
and those guns,
因为那些士兵
还有那些枪，
and those S-Boats are all new.
那些 S-Boats 都是新的。
That's a lot more
than the boys are expecting.
还有很多
比男孩们期待的还要多。
A month ago,
it was a dozen mechanics.
一个月前，
有十几个机械师。
Six drunk sailors.
六个醉酒的水手。
Two fat Spaniards.
两个胖西班牙人。
And a Nazi in a pear tree.
还有梨树上的纳粹。
I'd say,
we're gonna need more help.
我会说，
我们需要更多帮助。
You leave that to me.
你把这个留给我吧。
- Of course.
- (MAN GROANS)
- 当然。
-（男人呻吟）
(MAN YELLING IN GERMAN)
（男子用德语大喊）
- (GRUNTS)
- HERON: But right now...
-（咕噜声）
- HERON：但是现在……
- (MAN GROANS)
- ...you need to meet that man.
-（男人呻吟）
- ...你需要见见那个人。
(LAUGHING)
（笑）
(INTRIGUING MUSIC PLAYING)
（有趣的音乐播放）
HERON: Your man.
The reason you're here.
海伦：你的男人。
你来这里的原因。
MAN: Ah.
男人：啊。
The only thing
worse than a Nazi...
唯一的事情
比纳粹还坏……
is him.
是他。
(INTRIGUING MUSIC CONTINUES)
（有趣的音乐继续）
(KNOCKING AT DOOR)
（敲门）
(MUSIC FADES)
（音乐渐弱）
(DOOR OPENS)
（门打开）
(SOLDIER, IN GERMAN)
（士兵，德语）
(SOLDIER SPEAKING GERMAN)
（士兵说德语）
(IN ENGLISH)
I'm very disappointed, Heron.
（用英语讲）
我很失望，赫伦。
There are 16 crates
in my warehouse
有16个箱子
在我的仓库里
you have not yet
shipped to the mainland.
你还没有
运往大陆。
No need to fret, Herr Luhr.
不用担心，卢尔先生。
They'll still be delivered
by the agreed date.
他们仍然会被交付
在约定的日期之前。
That may be.
那可能。
But they take up valuable space.
但它们占用了宝贵的空间。
For this, I expect
为此，我期望
a significant reduction
in your fee.
显著减少
在你的费用中。
- HERON: I can do 5%...
- (SCOFFS)
- HERON：我可以做到 5%...
-（嘲笑）
...as a gesture of goodwill.
……作为一种善意的姿态。
Twenty. And don't waste
my precious time haggling.
二十。并且不要浪费
我讨价还价的宝贵时间。
MARJORIE: Well,
strictly speaking,
玛乔丽：嗯，
严格来讲，
there should be no reductions,
不应有任何减少，
since there's not yet been
any breach of contract.
因为还没有
任何违反合同的行为。
Five is more than polite,
20 rings like a sour note,
五不止于礼貌，
20响就像一个酸味的音符，
it jars.
它很吵。
It jars?
它罐子吗？
Am I being
accused of disharmony?
我是不是
被指责不和谐？
I take that
as a personal affront.
我认为
作为个人侮辱。
And I am supposing
you are not the secretary.
我假设
你不是秘书。
Miss Stewart is the contact
I said I'd arrange.
斯图尔特小姐是联系人
我说我会安排。
Ah, your New York gold contact?
啊，你的纽约黄金联系人吗？
I told you,
我告诉你了，
I already have
a satisfying arrangement.
我已经有了
令人满意的安排。
Have a seat.
请坐。
Thank you.
谢谢。
(HEINRICH SPEAKING GERMAN)
（海因里希说德语）
(IN ENGLISH) Well,
I hope I don't disappoint.
（英语）嗯，
我希望我不会失望。
(LAUGHS)
（笑）
I can't make a decision
on this presentation.
我无法做出决定
在本次演讲中。
Early days.
早些年。
Well, if early days
do come too soon,
好吧，如果早点
来得太早了，
and seasons change
with a Hunter's Moon.
和季节的变化
与猎人的月亮。
(IN GERMAN)
（在德国）
Hmm.
唔。
(IN ENGLISH)
I have to say, Heron,
（用英语讲）
我不得不说，海伦，
for all your flaws,
对于你所有的缺点，
you do have a habit
of pulling rabbits from hats.
你确实有一个习惯
从帽子里拉兔子。
(CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING)
（古典音乐演奏）
So, how much gold
do you wish to move,
那么，需要多少黄金
你想搬家吗
- Miss Stewart?
- (LIGHTER CLICKS)
- 斯图尔特小姐？
-（轻击声）
As much as you can find.
能找到多少就找多少。
As I mentioned before,
正如我之前提到的，
I do already have
a very profitable arrangement.
我已经有了
一个非常有利可图的安排。
And despite of your commentary,
尽管有你的评论，
I pride myself
on maintaining harmony.
我为自己感到骄傲
关于维护和谐。
Now, why should I entertain you?
现在，我为什么要招待你？
Because you'll make more money
and have lots of fun
因为你会赚更多的钱
并有很多乐趣
whilst doing so.
这样做的同时。
If I'm not good for my word,
don't pay me.
如果我不遵守诺言，
别付钱给我。
(IN GERMAN)
（在德国）
(LAUGHS)
（笑）
(IN ENGLISH) Bravo.
（英语）太棒了。
I will talk to my people
and then we'll rendezvous.
我会和我的人民交谈
然后我们会合。
Lovely.
迷人的。
When the sly red cat
barks at dawn,
当狡猾的红猫
黎明时吠叫，
and kills just for her pleasure,
并为了自己的快乐而杀人，
who shares the meal
the cat did steal
谁分享这顿饭
猫确实偷了
when both looked on in pleasure?
当两人都高兴地看着的时候？
Auf wiedersehen.
Auf wiedersehen。
(IN GERMAN)
（在德国）
(CHUCKLES)
（笑声）
(CLASSICAL MUSIC
CONTINUES PLAYING)
（古典音乐
继续播放）
(CLASSICAL MUSIC FADES)
（古典音乐渐弱）
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
（紧张的音乐播放）
(SIGHS)
（叹气）
(PEOPLE SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
（人们说话含糊不清）
(FLICKING LIGHTER)
（打火机闪烁）
The riddle was a nice touch.
这个谜语是一个很好的接触。
(SIGHS)
（叹气）
The hook's in.
钩子进来了
(CONTINUES FLICKING LIGHTER)
（继续闪烁打火机）
Now be careful
how you reel him in.
现在要小心
你如何把他卷入。
(INHALES)
（吸气）
I'll make sure
the harbor's empty
我会确定
港口空了
when the boys arrive.
当男孩们到达时。
How are you going to do that?
你打算怎么做？
I'll throw a party at my club.
我会在我的俱乐部举办一个聚会。
A costume party for the officers
为军官举办的化装舞会
and a second party at the dock
for the soldiers.
和码头的第二次聚会
对于士兵来说。
People like my parties.
人们喜欢我的聚会。
Everyone but Luhr.
除了卢尔之外的所有人。
That will be your job.
那将是你的工作。
All the rats
will follow the piper.
所有的老鼠
将跟随风笛手。
GEOFFREY: So,
if I understand correctly,
杰弗里：那么，
如果我理解正确的话
we're currently
here in La Palma.
我们目前
在拉帕尔马岛这里。
We'll sail around
German-controlled Africa
我们将四处航行
德国控制的非洲
to Fernando Po,
费尔南多·波，
which is just
north of the Equator,
这只是
赤道以北，
just off the West African coast.
就在西非海岸附近。
So that's the shortest route?
那么这是最短路线吗？
Yes, but we don't
want to go shorter.
是的，但我们不
想要更短。
Our priority is not to be seen.
我们的首要任务是不被人看到。
You mean, be seen again.
你的意思是，再次见到。
Again? Getting a little sloppy
on us now, Gussy?
再次？变得有点马虎
现在就轮到我们了，Gussy？
Had a run-in already?
已经有磨合了吗？
Never mind us, Apple, old boy.
别管我们，苹果，老男孩。
Remind me again
再次提醒我
how you found your nipples
attached to a car battery.
你是怎么找到你的乳头的
连接到汽车电池。
(CHUCKLING)
（咯咯笑）
Yes. Wasn't my fault.
是的。不是我的错。
Bad intelligence.
Plus it was almost worth it
智力不好。
而且这几乎是值得的
to watch
the heart-snatcher at work.
观看
工作中的夺心者。
I'm better known as a lover
than a fighter.
我更出名的是一个情人
比战士。
Jesus Christ!
耶稣基督！
If that's how you fight,
I'd hate to see you love.
如果这就是你战斗的方式
我不愿意看到你爱。
You don't have
to worry about that,
你没有
担心这个，
you're too pretty for me.
你对我来说太漂亮了。
Freddy, on the other hand...
另一方面，弗雷迪...
You'd have to catch me first.
你得先抓住我。
I do love to hunt.
我确实喜欢打猎。
You'd be lucky.
你会很幸运。
I'm really getting quite hot.
我真的变得很热了。
Anyway, my suggestion is
that we take this wider route.
无论如何，我的建议是
我们采取这条更广泛的路线。
It's obviously longer
明显更长了
but it should avoid
any awkward conversations
但应该避免
任何尴尬的对话
with German U-boats
or British warships.
与德国潜艇
或英国军舰。
Weather-dependent,
取决于天气，
we should make it there
in 15 days.
我们应该能到达那里
15 天内。
Agreed.
同意。
Haysey, do you think
you could manage that?
海西，你认为
你能做到吗？
Leave it to me, sir.
交给我吧，先生。
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
（戏剧性的音乐演奏）
(PEOPLE LAUGHING,
SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
（人们笑，
说话含糊不清）
- (MAN SHOUTS)
- (MUSIC FADES)
-（男人大喊）
-（音乐渐弱）
Just do as you're told
照你说的去做
- and get me another drink!
- (GLASSES CLINK)
- 再给我一杯饮料！
-（眼镜叮当声）
MAN: Captain, sir.
男人：船长，先生。
Can I get you something to eat?
我可以给你弄点吃的吗？
May I... Come this way.
我可以……这边过来吗？
- (OBJECTS CLATTERING)
- Take your hands off me.
-（物体碰撞声）
- 把你的手拿开。
(CAPTAIN EXHALES)
（船长呼气）
You know,
你知道，
I like you, Femi.
我喜欢你，费米。
But you touch me again
and you're going to jail.
但你又触碰了我
你会进监狱的。
Femi.
费米。
(CHATTER CONTINUES)
（闲聊继续）
I'll deal with him.
我来对付他。
Please take care
of Miss Stewart.
请保重
斯图尔特小姐的。
You know what you need,
Captain Binea?
你知道自己需要什么，
比内亚队长？
I know what I need.
我知道我需要什么。
But do you, Ricardo?
但你呢，里卡多？
You need another drink.
你需要再喝一杯。
Marty,
马蒂，
good stuff.
好东西。
Ricardo, that's why I love you.
里卡多，这就是我爱你的原因。
- You understand.
- (GLASS CLINKS)
- 你明白。
-（玻璃叮当声）
HERON: This is Fernando Po.
HERON：我是费尔南多·波。
Everybody's welcome.
欢迎大家。
Si... Everybody.
Si...大家。
Too many body I think.
我认为太多的身体。
(MAN LAUGHING)
（男人笑）
Armando?
阿曼多？
Have you fallen out
with our new friends?
你摔倒了吗
和我们的新朋友？
(SIGHS) It's not fair, Ricardo.
（叹气）这不公平，里卡多。
This is my harbor.
这是我的港湾。
I am in charge.
我是负责人。
Are they stepping on your toes?
他们踩到你的脚趾了吗？
They don't step, they stamp!
他们不是踩踏，而是跺脚！
They tell Captain Binea nothing.
他们什么也没告诉比尼亚船长。
(CHATTER STOPS)
（闲聊停止）
Only now do I hear
直到现在我才听到
the Duchessa
is leaving the harbor early.
公爵夫人
提前离开港口。
(CHATTER RESUMES)
（闲聊继续）
Well, good riddance.
好吧，摆脱了。
The harbor will be yours again.
港口将再次属于你。
When will you be free
of that ugly vessel?
你什么时候有空
那个丑陋的容器？
Three days earlier.
三天前。
Then we should
have another drink.
那么我们应该
再喝一杯。
To celebrate. Marty...
庆祝一下。马蒂...
Another round
for our Harbor Master.
再来一轮
为我们的港务长。
So, Captain, do you know
where they wish to relocate?
那么，船长，你知道吗？
他们希望搬迁到哪里？
It's neither cat nor dog
that kills for fun,
这既不是猫也不是狗
以杀人为乐，
it's the vixen, not another.
这是泼妇，不是另一个。
There's only two
that kill for fun,
只有两个
以杀人为乐，
my pretty friend,
我漂亮的朋友，
the fox and his human brother.
狐狸和他的人类兄弟。
- (LAUGHING)
- (MARJORIE CHUCKLES)
-（笑）
-（玛乔丽轻笑）
I believe I have
resolved your little riddle.
我相信我有
解决了你的小谜语。
Chapeau. You play well.
起首。你打得很好。
(TAPPING)
（窃听）
Speaking of foxes,
说起狐狸，
Horowitz and Meyer,
West 47th Street.
霍洛维茨和迈耶，
西47街。
Have you heard of them?
你听说过他们吗？
I don't believe I have, no.
我不相信我有，没有。
(LIGHTER CLINKS)
（打火机叮当声）
(CHATTER FADES)
（喋喋不休的声音消失）
(LIGHTER CLINKS SOFTLY)
（打火机轻轻叮当响）
They're the largest gold traders
他们是最大的黄金交易商
in Midtown New York
位于纽约市中心
and you haven't heard of them?
你还没有听说过他们吗？
I'm afraid I haven't, no.
恐怕我没有，没有。
I am familiar, of course,
with Horowitz and Haim.
我当然很熟悉，
与霍洛维茨和海姆。
But they're in the west side
of the city.
但他们在西边
城市的。
But then again,
但话又说回来，
I'm sure you already
knew that, didn't you?
我确定你已经
你知道这一点，不是吗？
I'm curious,
我很好奇，
how do you find
dealing with the Jew?
你怎么找到
与犹太人打交道？
Oh, dear. (CHUCKLES)
哦亲爱的。 （笑声）
I've slipped from one snare
我从一个网罗中滑落
only to find myself in another.
却发现自己在另一个人身上。
How shall I put this?
我该怎么说呢？
I fear your brilliant leader
我害怕你杰出的领袖
has mischaracterized
the ancient tribe of Jahuda.
已被错误描述
古老的贾胡达部落。
Their ability to not only
他们的能力不仅
survive 3,000 years
with a boot on their neck,
生存3000年
脖子上套着靴子，
but to prosper in spite of it...
但尽管如此，还是要繁荣......
I suspect it inspired
satanic jealousy within him.
我怀疑它的启发
他内心充满了撒旦的嫉妒。
In conclusion,
综上所述，
it looks as though
看起来好像
the lady doth protest too much.
这位女士抗议得太多了。
Is there a cherry to go
on this blasphemous cake,
有樱桃可去吗
在这亵渎的蛋糕上，
or have you finished?
或者你完成了吗？
(LAUGHS)
（笑）
(TAPPING)
（窃听）
I must confess,
我必须承认，
not only do I respect
and admire the Jew...
我不仅尊重
并钦佩犹太人......
I am one.
我孤身一人。
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
（紧张的音乐播放）
(LAUGHING)
（笑）
- (LAUGHING)
- (TENSE MUSIC FADES)
-（笑）
-（紧张的音乐渐渐消失）
(LAUGHING)
（笑）
MARJORIE: Kidding!
玛乔丽：开玩笑！
They're greedy rats.
他们是贪吃的老鼠。
I think this could be
我认为这可能是
the beginning
of a beautiful friendship.
开始
一段美好的友谊。
Then I shall throw a party
to celebrate.
然后我会举办一个聚会
庆祝。
I don't care for parties.
我不喜欢聚会。
Oh, spoilsport!
Everybody loves a party.
哦，糟蹋了！
每个人都喜欢聚会。
(TENSE WESTERN MUSIC PLAYING)
（紧张的西方音乐演奏）
The Duchessa's leaving
公爵夫人离开
three days earlier
than we thought.
三天前
比我们想像的。
If we don't tell
the Maid Honor,
如果我们不告诉
女仆荣誉，
they'll arrive too late.
他们会来得太晚了。
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
（模糊不清的喋喋不休）
OPERATOR: Incoming.
接线员：来了。
(SIGNAL BEEPING)
（信号蜂鸣声）
Contact.
接触。
MARJORIE: More Jerries
on the island than expected.
玛乔丽：更多杰瑞
岛上的情况比预想的要好。
Tin of corned beef's
out of pantry
罐头咸牛肉
从食品储藏室出来
three days early.
提前三天。
(SIGNAL BEEPING)
（信号蜂鸣声）
I'll take that.
我会接受的。
OPERATOR: It's confidential,
sir. For M only.
接线员：这是保密的，
先生。仅适用于 M。
When it comes
to make the extraction,
当谈到
进行提取，
it needs to be a very...
它需要是一个非常...
Sir. Message, sir.
先生。留言，先生。
(SIGNAL BEEPING)
（信号蜂鸣声）
GUS: More Jerries
on the island than expected.
GUS：更多杰瑞
岛上的情况比预想的要好。
Corned beef's out of the pantry
咸牛肉已经从食品储藏室里拿出来了
three days early.
提前三天。
Move faster.
动作快点。
M: Yes, but there's increased
U-boat sightings in the area.
M：是的，但是增加了
该地区的潜艇目击事件。
Sir.
先生。
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
（电话铃声）
OFFICER: The mission's
still proceeding.
官员：任务的
仍在进行中。
FREDDY: So, there's more
soldiers on the island
弗雷迪：所以，还有更多
岛上的士兵
and the boat's leaving earlier?
船要提前出发吗？
Yes.
是的。
Well, how are
we meant to move faster?
嗯，怎么样
我们的意思是要走得更快吗？
We can't move faster.
我们不能走得更快。
We're going as fast as we can.
我们会尽可能快地前进。
This is a fishing boat,
it's not a speedboat.
这是一艘渔船，
这不是快艇。
M: Prime Minister,
M：总理，
the Duchessa's leaving
Fernando Po in 12 days.
公爵夫人离开
12 天后费尔南多·波 (Fernando Po)。
On our current schedule,
按照我们目前的时间表，
they'll arrive
three days too late.
他们会到达
晚了三天。
Can it still be done?
还可以做吗？
M: We're still
awaiting a response
M：我们还在
等待回复
from Major Phillips.
来自菲利普斯少校。
If we can't move faster,
we'll go shorter.
如果我们不能走得更快
我们会走得更短。
We can get to Fernando Po
in 12 days.
我们可以去找费尔南多·波
12天内。
Hold on, you said
we couldn't go shorter.
坚持住，你说
我们不能再短了。
No, I said
we don't want to go shorter.
不，我说
我们不想走得更短。
He said we'll get
mowed down by a U-boat.
他说我们会得到
被U型潜艇击落。
Or worse,
picked up by the Brits.
或者更糟糕的是，
被英国人捡到了。
Their armada of destroyers
are crossing there.
他们的驱逐舰舰队
正在穿越那里。
FREDDY: We will literally
be sailing over U-boats.
弗雷迪：我们真的会
在U型潜艇上航行。
Sorry, lads, we go shorter.
抱歉，伙计们，我们走得更短了。
(THRILLING
WESTERN MUSIC PLAYING)
（惊险
西洋音乐演奏）
(AIRPLANES ENGINES RUMBLING)
（飞机引擎隆隆作响）
Drei, zwei, eins...
(CONTINUES SPEAKING GERMAN)
Drei，zwei，eins...
（继续说德语）
(FAINT EXPLOSIONS)
（微弱的爆炸声）
(MUSIC CRESCENDOES, FADES)
（音乐渐强、渐弱）
(MUTED EXPLOSIONS)
（无声的爆炸声）
(TENSE WESTERN MUSIC PLAYING)
（紧张的西方音乐演奏）
CHURCHILL: Gentlemen,
as I speak to you now,
丘吉尔：先生们，
正如我现在对你所说的那样，
London once again
再次伦敦
shudders beneath a Nazi
onslaught from the skies.
在纳粹的统治下不寒而栗
来自天空的猛攻。
And at such times,
在这样的时候，
the hearts of men
are stirred to duty.
男人的心
被搅拌去上班。
(OVER RADIO)
But you are not such men.
（通过无线电）
但你们不是这样的人。
You were not chosen
你没有被选中
for your conspicuous honor
or high ideals.
为了你的显赫荣誉
或崇高的理想。
You were chosen
你被选中了
because you are
the last resort.
因为你是
最后的手段。
The mission
you have been given
使命
你已被给予
is of a sort
never before undertaken.
是某种
以前从未进行过。
It demands ruthless men,
who will not hesitate
它需要无情的人，
谁会毫不犹豫
to stoop beneath
the conventions of war.
弯下腰
战争惯例。
Men who do not keep clean hands.
不保持双手清洁的男性。
Men like you.
像你这样的男人。
- (FAINT EXPLOSIONS)
- And yet, who still conspire
-（微弱的爆炸声）
- 然而，谁还在密谋
in their own
discordant harmony.
在他们自己的
不和谐的和谐。
Who know and yet do not care
that they may never return.
谁知道却不在乎
他们可能永远不会回来。
And who press onward
not for glory,
还有谁继续前进
不为荣耀，
or for duty, or for me,
或者为了职责，或者为了我，
but because you are men
who will not stop
但是因为你们是男人
谁不会停下来
until it is done.
直到完成。
Godspeed, gentlemen.
祝您好运，先生们。
(TENSE WESTERN MUSIC CONTINUES)
（紧张的西部音乐继续）
Uh... Chaps...
呃……伙计们……
That's a British destroyer.
那是一艘英国驱逐舰。
We should move.
我们应该搬家。
We can't outrun that, sir.
我们无法超越，先生。
Well, we've seen them,
they've seen us.
嗯，我们见过他们，
他们见过我们。
COMMANDER:
Hold fast, Maid Honor.
指挥官：
坚持住，女仆荣誉。
We're preparing
a boarding party.
我们正在准备
登机派对。
LASSEN: Hello, Captain!
拉森：你好，队长！
Nothing exciting here.
这里没什么令人兴奋的。
We're just Swedish fishermen.
我们只是瑞典渔民。
COMMANDER:
Step forward, Jorgensen!
指挥官：
前进吧，乔根森！
Jorgensen, you're Swedish.
乔根森，你是瑞典人。
Ask them where
they're heading, would you?
问他们在哪里
他们正在前进，你会吗？
(SPEAKING SWEDISH)
（说瑞典语）
(IN SWEDISH)
（瑞典语）
(IN ENGLISH) Not you, Lassen.
（英语）不是你，拉森。
Uh...
呃...
I want to hear March-Phillips
have a go.
我想听马奇·菲利普斯
试试吧。
Ah.
啊。
Fair enough.
很公平。
Game's up, Commander. (CHUCKLES)
游戏开始了，指挥官。 （笑声）
Can't blame a girl for trying.
不能责怪一个女孩的尝试。
Good effort, Major.
干得好，少校。
But I'm afraid you are going
to have to come with us.
但我担心你会走
必须和我们一起去。
May I ask under whose authority
请问在谁的授权下
we've been waylaid?
我们被伏击了？
On the orders of Admiral Pound.
根据庞德海军上将的命令。
(RADAR PINGS)
（雷达脉冲）
OPERATOR: First Lieutenant.
操作员：中尉。
You are pursuing
你正在追求
an unsanctioned
criminal enterprise
未经批准的
犯罪企业
in international waters.
在国际水域。
You're going to cause an upset.
你会引起不安。
I think we're a little
past upset, Commander.
我觉得我们有点
过去的不安，指挥官。
Stevens, what have you got?
史蒂文斯，你有什么？
STEVENS: I had a ping, sir.
史蒂文斯：先生，我检测到了。
The greedy little Nazi
贪婪的小纳粹
won't be satisfied
with holding most of Europe,
不会满足
拥有欧洲大部分地区，
he's after our own
green and pleasant land.
他在追寻我们自己的
绿色宜人的土地。
Well, thank God you're here
好吧，感谢上帝你在这里
with your little
wooden battleship
和你的小
木制战舰
and your five-man army.
还有你的五人军队。
- (PINGS)
- U-boat, bearing 273.
-（ping）
- U 型潜艇，方位 273。
- Sound the alarm.
- (ALARM BLARING)
- 拉响警报。
-（警报声）
Come aboard.
上船吧。
OFFICER: U-boat approaching.
Starboard side, sir.
军官：U 型潜艇正在接近。
右舷一侧，长官。
Battle stations!
战斗站！
Major, if you know
what's good for you,
少校，如果你知道的话
什么对你有好处，
- you'll head home.
- Very good, Commander.
- 你会回家。
- 很好，指挥官。
Haysey, get us away
from that torpedo magnet
海西，带我们走吧
从那个鱼雷磁铁
as quickly as possible.
尽快。
Aye, sir. Apple, man the stern.
好的，先生。苹果，船尾的人。
Freddy, on the main sail.
弗雷迪，在主帆上。
Lassen to the bow, now.
Untie that station!
拉森到船头，现在。
解开那个站！
LASSEN: Aye.
拉森：是的。
HENRY: Quickly now, lads!
亨利：快点，伙计们！
Hoist that foresail for us,
will you, boys?
为我们起航，
孩子们，你愿意吗？
FREDDY: Main sail ready to haul!
弗雷迪：主帆准备好牵引！
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
（紧张的音乐播放）
HENRY: All right, Freddy,
now raise that main sail!
亨利：好吧，弗雷迪，
现在升起主帆！
FREDDY: Aye.
弗雷迪：是的。
- (ALARM CONTINUES)
- OFFICER: Report sounding.
-（警报继续）
- 警官：报告测深。
- STEVENS: Bearing 163.
- (PINGS)
- 史蒂文斯：轴承 163。
-（ping）
(SAILORS SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
（水手们用德语喊叫）
HENRY: (IN ENGLISH)
Lassen, trim the main sail
亨利：（英语）
拉森，调整主帆
and then tie it off!
然后把它系起来！
LASSEN: How do you expect good?
拉森：你对好的事情有什么期待？
STEVENS: Report sounding.
史蒂文斯：报告探测。
Bearing 115.
轴承115。
- OFFICER: Fire depth charges.
- (PINGS)
- 军官：火力深水炸弹。
-（ping）
(LEVER CLICKS)
（杠杆点击）
(EXPLOSION BOOMING)
（爆炸声）
(SAILORS SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
（水手们含糊地喊叫）
(MUTED EXPLOSIONS)
（无声的爆炸声）
(ALARM BLARING)
（警报声响起）
(MUSIC FADES)
（音乐渐弱）
(DISTANT EXPLOSIONS)
（远处爆炸）
(PEOPLE SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
（人们说话含糊不清）
(INTRIGUING MUSIC PLAYING)
（有趣的音乐播放）
MARJORIE: So, this is your man
that gets things done?
玛乔丽：所以，这是你的男人
能把事情做好吗？
His name is Kamp Billy...
with a K.
他的名字叫坎普·比利……
与 K。
And he went
to an English boarding school?
他去了
去英国寄宿学校？
Not just any boarding school.
He went to Eton,
不仅仅是任何寄宿学校。
他去了伊顿公学，
the boarding school.
寄宿学校。
Right...
正确的...
(DISTANT GUNSHOT)
（远处枪声）
Then what's he doing here?
那他来这里做什么？
He's a prince.
他是一位王子。
A prince of what, exactly?
到底是什么王子？
- The Prince of Fernando Po!
- (GUNSHOT)
- 费尔南多·波王子！
-（枪声）
So, he's part pirate,
part aristocrat?
所以，他有一部分是海盗，
部分贵族？
Chic.
别致。
He's also
a part of our solution.
他也是
我们解决方案的一部分。
RH.
相对湿度。
(MUSIC FADES)
（音乐渐弱）
KB.
知识库。
He's back in town.
他回到城里了。
MAN: Chief.
男：长官。
(MAN SPEAKING YORUBA)
（讲约鲁巴语的男子）
(GUNSHOT)
（枪声）
(IN ENGLISH) Seems like
you always come bearing gifts.
（英语）看起来像
你总是带着礼物来。
Is she for me?
她是为了我吗？
- Good luck with that.
- (CHUCKLES)
- 祝你好运。
-（轻笑）
I'm not for you,
我不是为了你，
but these are.
但这些是。
Mmm. Goodies. Yummy.
嗯。好东西。好吃。
- (MEN GRUNT)
- (MAN SPEAKING YORUBA)
-（男人咕哝）
- （男子说约鲁巴语）
- (IN ENGLISH) Ade...
- Chief.
-（英语）阿德...
- 酋长。
ADEDAYO: Come on, come on.
阿德达约：来吧，来吧。
(MEN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
（男人说话含糊不清）
Someone has taste.
有人有品味。
Rarer than hens' teeth.
比母鸡的牙齿还稀有。
Well, RH tells me that KB
嗯，RH 告诉我 KB
is the only man to talk to
是唯一可以交谈的人
when it comes
to getting things done.
当谈到
把事情做好。
Why do I feel like
I've gone from being
为什么我感觉
我已经离开了
- the predator to the prey?
- (COCKS GUN)
- 捕食者对猎物？
- (旋塞枪)
(GUNSHOT)
（枪声）
(CLEARS THROAT)
（清嗓子）
Quite an entrance, young lady.
相当不错的入口，年轻的女士。
It's on the condition
that we sample them...
是有条件的
我们对它们进行采样...
now.
现在。
Ade, set the table.
艾德，摆桌子。
ADEDAYO: Chief.
阿德达约：队长。
(LAUGHING)
And then the Duke said,
（笑）
然后公爵说：
"Push it in till it stops!"
“把它推进去，直到它停止为止！”
(ALL LAUGHING)
（大家都笑了）
You are quite the weapon.
你真是个武器。
I was right,
我是对的，
I was the prey.
我是猎物。
I'll help you
because I don't like Nazis.
我会帮你
因为我不喜欢纳粹。
Not because they're Nazis
but because they're gauche.
不是因为他们是纳粹分子
但因为他们很粗鲁。
I'll give you a tug
and 12 of my best men,
我给你拉一下
和我最好的12个人，
including yours truly.
包括你真正的。
But if I'm gonna help you,
who's gonna help me?
但如果我要帮助你的话
谁来帮助我？
Because you're
not a soldier, RH.
因为你是
不是士兵，RH。
No, but she is.
不，但她是。
She'll outshoot your best man.
她会超越你的伴郎。
(BLOWS RASPBERRY)
（吹覆盆子）
(GUNSHOT)
（枪声）
(COCKS GUN)
（旋塞枪）
(GUNSHOT)
（枪声）
(COCKS GUN)
（旋塞枪）
(GUNSHOTS)
（枪声）
(BLOWS)
（吹）
I told you.
我告诉你了。
- No!
- 不！
(MYSTERIOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
（神秘的音乐响起）
MARJORIE: Stork delivery. Check.
玛乔丽：鹳鸟送来的。查看。
Check.
查看。
Twenty-three boys. Check.
二十三个男孩。查看。
- (SIGNAL BEEPING)
- Stork delivery.
-（信号蜂鸣声）
- 鹳交付。
Twenty-three boys.
二十三个男孩。
Seventeen girls.
十七个女孩。
Meeting point 20 kilometers
outside Fernando Po.
集合地点20公里
费尔南多·波城外。
The rendezvous with Heron.
与海伦的约会。
Can you get us there?
你能带我们去那里吗？
If the weather holds,
如果天气好的话，
I can, sir.
我可以，先生。
(MYSTERIOUS MUSIC CONTINUES)
（神秘的音乐继续）
Twenty quid says
this doesn't end well.
二十英镑说
这结局并不好。
For who?
为了谁？
For them.
对于他们来说。
You can't bet on yourself,
Haysey. That's match-fixing.
你不能把赌注押在自己身上
海西。这就是比赛造假。
Let's do it.
我们开始做吧。
Heron, it's been too long.
海伦，好久不见了。
Good to see you, Gus.
很高兴见到你，格斯。
Apple.
苹果。
This is Kamp Billy,
the Prince of Fernando Po.
这是坎普比利，
费尔南多·波亲王。
Your Highness.
殿下。
He's agreed to help us.
他同意帮助我们。
Forgive me, but...
请原谅我，但是...
I have a peculiar feeling
that we've met before.
我有一种奇特的感觉
我们以前见过。
I get that a lot.
I'm extremely well-traveled.
我对此深有体会。
我经常出差。
(CHUCKLES) No, no.
It's a particular sense.
（轻笑）不，不。
这是一种特殊的感觉。
I don't suppose
you played cricket, did you?
我不认为
你打板球，是吗？
(CHUCKLES)
（笑声）
Captained Eton. '21 to '22.
伊顿队长。 '21 至 '22。
I knew I knew your face!
我就知道我认识你的脸！
Right next
to the trophy cabinet.
下一个
到奖杯柜。
An eight-foot-tall
huge portrait.
一个八英尺高
巨大的肖像。
Yes, exactly that!
是的，正是如此！
One eye on the boundary...
一只眼睛盯着边界……
BOTH: ...one eye on the pub.
两人：……一只眼睛盯着酒吧。
Bloody glad to have you aboard.
非常高兴你能加入。
KAMP BILLY: Bloody good
to be here, old boy.
坎普比利： 太棒了
来这里，老男孩。
I'm very bored
我感到很无聊
with these Nazis making
a nuisance of themselves.
与这些纳粹分子一起
他们自己的麻烦。
I mean,
it's terrible for business.
我是说，
这对生意来说太糟糕了。
I'm only too pleased
我简直太高兴了
to help you
serve them a bloody nose.
来帮你
让他们流鼻血。
That's a commendable attitude.
这是一种值得称赞的态度。
So, what's your plan?
那么，你的计划是什么？
Apple.
苹果。
We're going
to sink the Duchessa,
本来打算
沉没公爵夫人号，
plus the two tugs.
加上两个拖船。
Crippling Hitler's
Atlantic fleet of U-boats.
残害希特勒
大西洋舰队的U型潜艇。
Very good.
非常好。
The thing is,
our old friends the Nazis
事情是，
我们的老朋友纳粹
aren't making it the easiest.
并没有让它变得最简单。
We're outnumbered
two hundred to five.
我们寡不敌众
两百比五。
There's a few more soldiers
than we anticipated.
还有几个士兵
比我们预期的。
I think that we're gonna have
我想我们将会有
to find ourselves
a few more strapping lads.
找到我们自己
还有几个身材魁梧的小伙子。
Ade...
阿德...
(SPEAKING YORUBA)
（约鲁巴语）
(INTRIGUING
WESTERN MUSIC PLAYING)
（有趣的
西洋音乐演奏）
(IN ENGLISH) Right...
（英语）对...
(CHOMPING)
（咀嚼）
Yes, I think that will do.
是的，我想这样就可以了。
We brought some weapons
if you need.
我们带了一些武器
如果你需要。
You hold onto those.
We brought our own.
你抓住那些。
我们带了自己的。
(SPEAKING YORUBA)
（约鲁巴语）
(IN ENGLISH) Oyah!
Show them the iron!
（英语）噢！
给他们看铁！
(ADEDAYO SPEAKING YORUBA)
（阿德达约讲约鲁巴语）
(IN ENGLISH) Marvelous.
（英语）太棒了。
KAMP BILLY: You do know
the Duchessa is
坎普比利：你知道
公爵夫人是
more than 200 feet
from the harbor side?
超过200英尺
从港口一侧？
And she's in full glare
of the lights.
而她却在众目睽睽之下
的灯。
She's not gonna be easy to sink
她不会轻易沉没
without attracting
unwanted attention.
不吸引
不必要的关注。
Yes. That's why Heron
will plant a bomb
是的。这就是为什么苍鹭
会安放炸弹
to blow the lights,
before we paddle in
吹灯，
在我们划桨之前
and rig the hull
with explosives.
并安装船体
与炸药。
By the time
the explosives detonate,
到......的时候
炸药爆炸，
we'll be heading home.
我们要回家了。
If I had it my way,
a shot'll never be fired.
如果我按照自己的方式行事的话
永远不会开枪。
And how often
do you have it your way?
以及多久一次
你有办法吗？
Depends on who you ask, old boy.
这取决于你问谁，老男孩。
(KAMP BILLY CHUCKLES)
（坎普·比利轻笑）
GUS: Gentlemen...
格斯：先生们……
- Ade.
- Chief.
- 阿德。
- 酋长。
- Prepare the men.
- (ADEDAYO SPEAKING YORUBA)
- 准备人员。
- （阿德达约说约鲁巴语）
I'll take that 20
whenever you're ready, Freddy.
我要那20个
只要你准备好，弗雷迪。
(INDISTINCT ANNOUNCEMENT
OVER SPEAKERS)
（含糊其辞的公告
扬声器）
MARJORIE: The Duchessa
will be gone by the morning.
玛乔丽：公爵夫人
到早上就会消失。
- Can you manage that?
- (BOMB CLICKING)
- 你能做到吗？
-（炸弹点击）
It's two wires and a tick-tock.
它是两根电线和一个滴答声。
I'm sure I can cope.
我确信我能应付。
It's not me you should be
worried about.
你应该不是我
担心。
I've never
taken a Nazi to a party.
我从来没有
带纳粹去参加聚会。
Just don't end up
at one of his parties.
只是不要结束
在他的一个聚会上。
Don't worry about me.
别担心我。
I'm gonna have
my own little party.
我将会有
我自己的小聚会。
(MEN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
（男人说话含糊不清）
(MUSIC FADES)
（音乐渐弱）
GUS: Drink for the boys,
on His Majesty's government.
GUS：给孩子们喝一杯，
关于国王陛下的政府。
Ordinarily,
I'd bite your hand off,
按说，
我会咬掉你的手
as I have been known
to love a pound note.
据我所知
喜欢一英镑纸币。
(SPEAKING YORUBA)
（约鲁巴语）
(IN ENGLISH)
But on this occasion,
（用英语讲）
但在这一次，
the drinks are on me.
饮料由我来。
However,
然而，
if His Majesty's government
was handing out titles...
如果国王陛下的政府
正在分发头衔...
You're already a prince,
old boy.
你已经是王子了
老男孩。
There's Prince
of Fernando Po, but...
那里有王子
费尔南多·波，但是……
a Knight of the Realm
has a certain antiquity to it.
王国的骑士
它有一定的古老性。
Arise, Sir Kamp Billy.
起来，坎普·比利爵士。
You're a good man, Gus.
你是个好人，格斯。
Good luck, Billy.
祝你好运，比利。
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
（悬疑的音乐播放）
(MACHINERY WHIRRING)
（机器呼呼声）
Hola!
你好！
Buenas tardes, companeros!
Buenas tardes，同伴们！
(CLICKS)
（点击）
(SOLDIER, IN GERMAN)
（士兵，德语）
(MUSIC TURNS DRAMATIC)
（音乐变得戏剧化）
(IN GERMAN)
（在德国）
(GUNSHOTS)
（枪声）
(GUN CLICKS)
(SCREAMING)
（尖叫）
- (BODY SLIDES, THUDS)
- (MUSIC FADES)
-（身体滑动，重击）
-（音乐渐弱）
(BOMB TICKING)
（炸弹滴答作响）
(GENTLE PIANO MUSIC PLAYING)
（轻柔的钢琴曲演奏）
My Herr, you have a visitor.
我的先生，您有访客。
Ta-da!
哒哒！
(IN SING-SONG VOICE)
Cleopatra needs her Caesar.
（歌声）
克利奥帕特拉需要她的凯撒。
Put it on.
穿上。
(SNORTS)
（哼哼）
Thank you, Timothy.
谢谢你，蒂莫西。
One second.
一秒。
Timothy...
蒂莫西...
I have a counter offer.
我有还盘。
Let's put
this dressing up aside.
让我们把
这打扮放在一边。
It's for children.
And we are not children.
这是给孩子们的。
而且我们不是孩子。
Let's make our own party.
让我们举办我们自己的派对吧。
A dark party.
一场黑暗的派对。
A dark Nazi party.
一个黑暗的纳粹党。
With music, lubrication
and a handsome Nazi.
配合音乐、润滑
还有一个英俊的纳粹分子。
Since I've been here,
自从我来到这里，
I've been bitten by things
that croak and slither,
我被东西咬了
那呱呱叫和滑行的声音，
scorpions nest in my boots
and I can't sleep
蝎子在我的靴子里筑巢
我无法入睡
for the relentless howl
of jungle entropy.
为了无情的嚎叫
丛林熵。
Tonight,
今晚，
I'm going to that party,
and you are taking me.
我要去参加那个聚会
你正在带我。
Now, put it on.
现在，穿上它。
(CLICKS TONGUE) Oh.
（卡嚓舌头）哦。
Very well.
很好。
(EXCITING MUSIC PLAYING)
（激动人心的音乐演奏）
(PEOPLE SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
（人们说话含糊不清）
(LAUGHTER)
（笑声）
WOMAN: Ah! Hola!
女人：啊！ 你好！
We move when the lights go out.
灯灭后我们就移动。
- (WOMAN WHOOPING)
- (BAND PLAYING SWING MUSIC)
-（女人呼喊）
- （乐队演奏摇摆乐）
(MAN LAUGHING)
（男人笑）
All right, Ricardo,
好吧，里卡多，
today you're El Capitan.
今天你是El Capitan。
Armando, the bar is yours.
阿曼多，酒吧是你的了。
Use it. Abuse it at your will.
用它。随心所欲地滥用它。
BINEA: (CHUCKLES)
That's why I love you.
比内亚：（轻笑）
这就是为什么我爱你。
Come with me, handsome.
跟我来吧，帅哥。
(BINEA SPEAKING SPANISH)
（比内亚说西班牙语）
HERON: I need you
to keep the men happy.
海伦：我需要你
为了让男人们开心。
How happy?
多么高兴？
(BAND CONTINUES PLAYING
SWING MUSIC)
（乐队继续演奏
摇摆乐）
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATION)
（含糊不清的对话）
MARJORIE: Mmm.
玛乔丽：嗯。
Are the rats in the nest?
老鼠在窝里吗？
You won't find a German,
Spanish or Italian officer
你找不到德国人
西班牙或意大利官员
anywhere else tonight.
今晚还有其他地方。
- (SWING MUSIC CONTINUES)
- (PEOPLE CHEERING)
-（摇摆乐继续）
-（人们欢呼）
HERON: Between the beer fest
at the harbor
HERON：在啤酒节之间
在港口
and this little get-together,
还有这次小小的聚会，
that'll be 90% of the soldiers
away from the dock.
那将是90%的士兵
远离码头。
The charge is set
to blow the harbor lights
收费已设定
吹灭港口灯光
in 30 minutes.
30分钟后。
Can you keep him here that long?
你能把他留在这里这么久吗？
Silly boy, silly question.
Look at the dress.
愚蠢的孩子，愚蠢的问题。
看看这件衣服。
(MAN CHEERS)
（男人欢呼）
(LAUGHS)
（笑）
(TRUMPET FLARES)
（喇叭信号弹）
Hi.
你好。
So, you call this a party?
所以，你管这叫派对？
MARJORIE: This is just
the thin end of the wedge.
玛乔丽：这只是
楔子的薄端。
I've created a performance
just for you.
我创作了一场表演
只为你。
Well, I could show you
a real party.
好吧，我可以告诉你
一个真正的聚会。
(MARJORIE CHUCKLES)
（玛乔丽轻笑）
(IN ITALIAN)
（用意大利语）
(PEOPLE CHEERING, APPLAUDING)
（人们欢呼、鼓掌）
- (LAUGHS)
- (FRANTIC MUSIC PLAYING)
-（笑）
-（疯狂的音乐播放）
(IN ITALIAN)
（用意大利语）
(IN ENGLISH)
Why do I care, Spaghetti?
（用英语讲）
我为什么要关心，意大利面？
Pizza.
比萨。
Excuse me
while I powder my nose.
打扰一下
当我搽鼻涕的时候。
- What, again?
- (SCOFFS)
- 又是什么？
-（嘲笑）
Don't panic, Caesar.
Brush up on your Italian.
别惊慌，凯撒。
温习一下意大利语。
Your gift needs to be wrapped.
你的礼物需要包装。
Keep those officers
drinking, please.
留住那些军官
请喝酒。
- Of course. Okay.
- Thank you, Femi.
- 当然。好的。
- 谢谢你，费米。
The Duchessa's hull
has been reinforced.
公爵夫人号的船体
已得到加强。
It won't sink.
它不会沉没。
We need to stop the mission.
我们需要停止任务。
(FRANTIC MUSIC CONTINUES)
（疯狂的音乐继续）
That's going to be hard to do.
这将很难做到。
MARJORIE: Listen to me.
玛乔丽：听我说。
Our mission will fail.
我们的使命将会失败。
The explosives won't work
炸药不起作用
because he's reinforced it
to be unsinkable.
因为他强化了它
不沉的。
You have to stop them now.
你现在必须阻止他们。
But the charge is about
to blow the lights.
但收费约为
吹灯。
(BOMB TICKING)
（炸弹滴答作响）
Well, if you can't
stop the lights,
好吧，如果你不能
停止灯光，
stop the men.
阻止男人们。
Luhr must not leave this party.
鲁尔不能离开这个政党。
I'll keep him busy. Go, now.
我会让他忙起来。现在出发。
(MUSIC INTENSIFIES)
（音乐响起）
(MUSIC FADES)
（音乐渐弱）
(BAND PLAYING SWING MUSIC)
（乐队演奏摇摆乐）
GUS: And we're off.
GUS：我们出发了。
GEOFFREY: Gus, wait.
杰弗里：格斯，等等。
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
（紧张的音乐播放）
(SIGNAL BEEPING)
（信号蜂鸣声）
Stork to Maid,
Stork to Maid, come in.
鹳鸟对女仆，
鹳鸟对女仆说，进来吧。
Channel five.
第五频道。
GUS: (OVER RADIO)
This is Maid. Switching to 20.
格斯：（通过无线电）
这是女仆。切换到 20。
Go ahead.
继续。
Tin of corned beef
can't be cracked.
罐头咸牛肉
无法破解。
The ship cannot be sunk.
船不会沉没。
Explosives will fail.
炸药会失败。
It's Stork, sir.
这是鹳鸟，先生。
Put him on open speaker.
将他放在开放式扬声器上。
HERON: Corned beef
can't be cracked.
HERON：咸牛肉
无法破解。
Stork, this is M.
鹳鸟，这是M。
Never mind the corned beef.
Just find a way.
别介意咸牛肉。
就找个办法吧。
- Over.
- Pound incoming, sir.
- 超过。
- 英镑来了，先生。
- HERON: Repeat...
- Switch that off.
- HERON：重复...
- 把它关掉。
- We must...
- (TURNS OFF RADIO)
-我们必须...
-（关闭收音机）
(DOOR OPENS)
（门打开）
Stop this immediately.
立即停止这种行为。
What you are doing ends now,
你正在做的事现在结束了
or every last one of you
will be subject to a tribunal.
或你们每一个最后的人
将受法庭管辖。
Is that clear?
明白了吗？
I don't know what
you're talking about, sir.
我不知道什么
你说的是，先生。
Is that correct, Sergeant?
是这样吗，中士？
HERON: (OVER RADIO)
Hold position.
海伦：（通过无线电）
坚守阵地。
GUS: How long, Stork?
GUS：要多久，鹳？
- HERON: Awaiting orders.
- Give me that.
- HERON：等待命令。
- 给我那个。
HERON: Stand by.
HERON：待命。
March-Phillips,
马奇·菲利普斯，
this is Admiral Pound
giving you a direct order.
这是庞德海军上将
给你一个直接的命令。
Abort this mission now.
立即中止此任务。
(OVER SPEAKERS)
I will make sure that
（通过扬声器）
我会确保
none of you see
the light of day again.
你们都没有看到
重见天日。
You will spend
the rest of your lives
你将花费
你的余生
locked up
at His Majesty's pleasure.
被锁起来
遵照陛下的意愿。
That includes all of you.
这包括你们所有人。
Geoffrey Appleyard,
杰弗里·阿普尔亚德，
Anders Lassen,
安德斯·拉森，
- Freddy Buzz...
- GUS: I'm sorry...
-弗雷迪·巴兹...
- 格斯：对不起……
...and Henry Hayes.
...和亨利·海耶斯。
Can't quite make out
不太明白
- what you're saying.
- (RADIO STATIC CRACKLING)
- 你在讲些什么。
-（无线电静电爆裂声）
Bye.
再见。
- Is... Is that clear?
- (RADIO STATIC CRACKLES)
- 是……清楚了吗？
-（无线电静电爆裂声）
GUS: Sorry? What?
GUS：抱歉？什么？
I can't...
I can't quite hear you.
我不能...
我听不太清楚。
(HESITATES)
（犹豫）
GUS: Please... fuck off.
GUS：请...滚开。
(RECEIVER CLATTERS)
（接收器卡哒声）
You and your operation
are reckless, Brigadier.
您和您的运营
是鲁莽的，准将。
I will personally
advise parliament
我个人会
向议会提供建议
to have the Prime Minister
removed from office.
有首相
被免职。
And I am going to shut you down.
我会关闭你的。
Message received
loud and clear, sir.
收到消息
响亮而清晰，先生。
I suggest you also
fuck off, Sergeant.
我建议你也
滚蛋吧，中士。
Fleming, contact March-Phillips.
弗莱明，请联系马奇-菲利普斯。
- (RADIO CLICKS)
- (STATIC CRACKLES)
-（广播点击）
-（静态爆裂声）
Lily, get me
the Prime Minister on hotline.
莉莉，来找我吧
总理热线电话。
- LILY: Right away, sir.
- Come in, 01.
- 莉莉：马上，先生。
- 进来吧，01。
Come in, do you receive?
进来吧，收到了吗？
(RECEIVER CLATTERS)
（接收器卡哒声）
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
（电话铃声）
- Yes?
- M: Prime Minister,
- 是的？
- M：总理，
I'm afraid
we've been discovered.
我害怕
我们被发现了。
(SIGHS)
（叹气）
There was a mole in our midst
我们中间有一颗内奸
and Admiral Pound
和庞德海军上将
has ordered the mission
to be aborted.
已下令执行任务
被中止。
He wants to have parliament
remove you from office.
他想要议会
将你撤职。
The mission must continue.
使命必须继续下去。
01, this is base. Over.
01，这是基地。超过。
CHURCHILL: Tell Pound
if he has a problem,
丘吉尔：告诉庞德
如果他有问题，
to take it up with me.
He knows where I live.
跟我一起解决这个问题。
他知道我住在哪里。
Tell the men to press on.
告诉队员们继续前进。
I'm afraid we've lost
all communication, sir.
恐怕我们已经输了
所有通讯，先生。
There must be
something that we can do.
必须有
我们可以做的事情。
The only thing
I can do is remind you,
唯一的事情
我能做的就是提醒你，
the reason
we chose March-Phillips
原因
我们选择了马奇-菲利普斯
is because
he doesn't follow orders.
是因为
他不服从命令。
Then let's hope we chose well.
那么希望我们选择得好。
(RECEIVER CLATTERS)
（接收器卡哒声）
(SIGHS)
（叹气）
The Duchessa's hull
has been reinforced.
公爵夫人号的船体
已得到加强。
Which means she can't be sunk.
这意味着她不能沉没。
At least not with the amount
of explosives we're carrying.
至少没有金额
我们携带的炸药。
Just wondering how and when
exactly this took place.
只是想知道如何以及何时
这正是发生的。
It's not important
how and when, it's happened.
这并不重要
它是如何以及何时发生的。
Well, it is
kind of important, Gus.
嗯，是的
有点重要，格斯。
I don't care
about the prison time,
我不在乎
关于入狱时间，
but I do care about finishing
what we've started.
但我确实关心完成
我们已经开始的事情。
Thank you, Freddy.
谢谢你，弗雷迪。
There must be
some sort of mistake.
必须有
某种错误。
You can't just reinforce...
你不能只是强化...
There's no mistake, Haysey.
没有错，海西。
I'm just lost about
how and when exactly...
我只是迷失了
具体如何以及何时...
- Enough!
- (TABLE RATTLES)
- 足够的！
-（桌子发出嘎嘎声）
Why don't we sink the tug boats?
为什么我们不击沉拖船呢？
Get rid of the shuttle
to the U-boats.
摆脱班车
到U型潜艇。
It's not enough.
这不够。
They'll replace them in a week.
他们将在一周内更换它们。
Why don't we steal them?
我们为什么不偷它们呢？
We can use Billy's boat
我们可以使用比利的船
to drag the Duchessa
out of the harbor
拖动公爵夫人
出港
and steal the other two
German tug boats
并偷走另外两个
德国拖船
that service the U-boats.
为U型潜艇提供服务。
And how are
we supposed to do that?
怎么样？
我们应该这样做吗？
Not only is she double-plated,
weighing twice as much,
她不仅是双盘，
重量是原来的两倍，
but you'd need a full crew
to move a ship that size.
但你需要一个完整的工作人员
移动那么大的船。
The tug boats are the crew.
拖船就是船员。
We tow the Duchessa
out to the ocean
我们拖曳公爵夫人
出海
and, well, steal the lot.
然后，好吧，偷很多东西。
Then what?
We still can't sink them.
然后呢？
我们仍然无法击沉它们。
We don't need to.
我们不需要。
We sail
into international waters
我们扬帆起航
进入国际水域
and hand everything
over to the Navy.
并把一切都交给
交给海军。
They're following us anyway,
无论如何他们都在跟踪我们
so they'll be more than happy
to see us again.
所以他们会非常高兴
再次见到我们。
And what about the anchor?
那么锚呢？
Have you seen the size of it?
你见过它的大小吗？
If we're gonna
actually start to move her,
如果我们要
真正开始感动她，
their S-boats
will catch us in seconds.
他们的S艇
几秒钟内就会抓住我们。
Well, what are you going to do
好吧，你打算做什么
with all the explosives
you brought, Freddy?
和所有的炸药
你带来了吗，弗雷迪？
We'll use them
to blow the anchor.
我们将使用它们
起锚。
We'll rig the S-boats
so they can't follow,
我们将装备 S 艇
所以他们无法跟随，
rig the fuel reserve
that supplies the U-boats,
操纵燃料储备
为U型潜艇提供补给，
and then, well, blow the lot up.
然后，好吧，炸毁这一切。
That fuel explosion's
gonna bring
那次燃油爆炸
会带来
everyone and their mother
down to the harbor.
每个人和他们的母亲
下到港口。
GEOFFREY: We set the fuse,
杰弗里：我们设置了保险丝，
so that the fuel dump blows
once we're outside the harbor.
以便燃油堆爆炸
一旦我们出了港口。
Then we sneak out quietly.
然后我们悄悄溜出去。
Not bad.
不错。
(CHUCKLES) It's very greedy.
（笑）它非常贪婪。
- Well, I'm in.
- LASSEN: Well,
- 嗯，我进来了。
- 拉森：嗯，
I'm not leaving until I have
a barrel full of Nazi hearts.
我不会离开，直到我完成为止
一桶装满纳粹之心。
I'll do whatever
you tell me to do, sir.
我会做任何事
你告诉我怎么做，先生。
Gentlemen,
先生们，
let's steal some boats.
让我们偷一些船吧。
(GUS SIGHS)
（格斯叹气）
Turns out she's double-plated,
so change of plans.
原来她是双盘，
所以改变计划。
We're going
to steal the boats instead.
本来打算
而是偷船。
(SCOFFS)
（嘲笑）
Is that even possible?
这可能吗？
I'm not entirely sure.
我不太确定。
But if you're up for it,
so are we.
但如果你愿意的话
我们也是。
And you know what that means.
你知道这意味着什么。
A lot more blood
and a lot more sweat.
血多了很多
还有更多的汗水。
Hopefully not any of ours,
old boy.
希望不是我们任何人，
老男孩。
I don't think we can do this
without you, Billy.
我认为我们做不到
没有你，比利。
(KAMP BILLY SIGHS)
（坎普·比利叹息）
Well, I'm up for it if you are.
好吧，如果你愿意的话，我愿意。
I think we're gonna
need your tug.
我想我们会
需要你的拖船。
(KAMP BILLY CHUCKLES)
（坎普·比利轻笑）
Haysey and I will
take a stroll along the harbor
海西和我会
沿着港口漫步
and take out
any soldiers still patrolling.
并取出
任何仍在巡逻的士兵。
Freddy will bring
his dinghy around
弗莱迪将带来
他的小艇在周围
and take care of the S-boats.
并照顾S艇。
We'll meet you by the tug boats.
我们将在拖船上与您会面。
KAMP BILLY: And the Duchessa?
坎普·比利：那么公爵夫人呢？
That's Apple and me.
那是苹果和我。
We'll take care of any crew
and blow the anchor.
我们会照顾任何船员
并吹锚。
GEOFFREY:
And destroy their comms.
杰弗里：
并摧毁他们的通讯。
Not sure
what you'll meet on board.
没有把握
您将在船上遇到什么。
Take my top boy
and two more of my men.
带走我的顶级男孩
还有我的另外两个人。
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
（紧张的音乐播放）
Gentlemen, let's prepare.
先生们，让我们做好准备吧。
? Oh, the shark, babe
?哦，鲨鱼，宝贝
? Has such teeth, dear
? 亲爱的，有这样的牙齿
? And he shows them
pearly white
? 他向他们展示了
珍珠白
(CROWD CHEERING)
（人群欢呼）
? Just a jack-knife
? 只是一把折刀
? Has old MacHeath, dear
? 有老麦克希斯，亲爱的
? And he keeps it out of sight
? 他把它放在看不见的地方
? You know
when that shark bites
? 你知道
当鲨鱼咬人时
? With his teeth, dear
? 用他的牙齿，亲爱的
? Scarlet billows
starts to spread
? 猩红的巨浪
开始蔓延
? Fancy gloves, oh,
wears old MacHeath, dear
? 漂亮的手套，哦，
亲爱的，穿着旧麦克希斯的衣服
? So there's never,
never a trace of red
? 所以从来没有，
没有一丝红色
? On the sidewalk
? 在人行道上
? On Sunday morning,
don't you know
? 周日早上，
你不知道吗
? Lies a body
? 躺着一具尸体
? Oozing life
? 渗出生命
? And someone sneakin'
around the corner
? 有人偷偷摸摸
就在拐角处
? Could that be
old Mack the Knife?
? 难道是这样吗
老麦克刀？
? There's a tug boat
? 有一艘拖船
? Down by the river,
don't cha know
? 在河边，
你不知道
(EXHALES)
（呼气）
? Where a cement bag's
just a-drooping on down...
? 水泥袋的地方
只是一个-下垂...
- (SONG FADES)
- (TENSE GRAND MUSIC PLAYING)
-（歌声渐弱）
-（紧张的宏大音乐演奏）
(SHIP MOTOR WHIRRING)
（船舶马达的呼呼声）
(GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
（枪声安静）
(SAILORS SPEAKING IN GERMAN)
（水手们用德语说话）
(RUSTLING)
（沙沙声）
- (GUN FIRES QUIETLY)
- (GRUNTS)
-（枪声安静）
-（咕噜声）
(SOLDIER SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
（士兵含糊其辞）
Not yet.
还没有。
(SOLDIERS CLEARING THROAT,
CLAMORING)
（士兵们清嗓子，
吵闹）
Mein Herr.
我的先生。
(IN GERMAN)
（在德国）
Haysey...
海西...
(GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
（枪声安静）
(GUS LAUGHING)
（格斯笑）
(SINGING IN GERMAN)
（用德语唱歌）
(CROWD GASPS, CHEERS)
（人群喘息、欢呼）
(TENSE GRAND MUSIC CRESCENDOES)
（紧张的宏大音乐渐强）
- (MUSIC FADES)
- (SINGING CONTINUES MUTEDLY)
-（音乐渐弱）
-（歌声继续低声）
(SPEAKING IN GERMAN)
（用德语发言）
(INTENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
（激烈的音乐演奏）
HENRY: (IN ENGLISH) Up there
on the left, sir.
亨利：（用英语）在上面
在左边，先生。
GUS: Yes.
格斯：是的。
- (GUN FIRES QUIETLY)
- (SOLDIER SCREAMS)
-（枪声安静）
-（士兵尖叫声）
- (CRASHES)
- (GUS LAUGHS)
-（崩溃）
-（格斯笑）
He made a crash!
他撞车了！
(SOLDIER SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
（士兵含糊不清地喊叫）
(SPEAKS GERMAN)
（说德语）
- (GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
- (SOLDIERS GROAN)
-（枪声安静）
-（士兵们呻吟）
- (SOLDIER SHOUTS IN GERMAN)
- (GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
-（士兵用德语喊叫）
-（枪声安静）
We could take that car, sir.
Save us some shoe leather.
我们可以乘坐那辆车，先生。
为我们节省一些鞋革。
(GRUNTS)
（咕噜声）
(CONTINUES SINGING)
（继续唱歌）
(INTENSE MUSIC CONTINUES)
（激烈的音乐继续）
(SINGING MUTEDLY)
（低声歌唱）
(AUDIBLY IN ENGLISH)
? Look out, old Macky is back ?
（可听到英语）
? 小心，老麦基回来了 ?
- (MUSIC STOPS)
- (INDISTINCT CONVERSATION)
-（音乐停止）
-（模糊的对话）
(IN GERMAN)
（在德国）
- (GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
- (THUD)
-（枪声安静）
-（轰鸣声）
(VEHICLE APPROACHING)
（车辆接近）
MAN: (IN ENGLISH) Incoming.
男士：（用英语）来了。
(ENGINE STOPS)
（发动机停止）
(DOORS OPEN, CLOSE)
（门打开、关闭）
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
（脚步声靠近）
Papers please.
请提供论文。
- Commander. (EXHALES)
- All good, Freddy?
- 指挥官。 （呼气）
- 一切都好吗，弗雷迪？
Charges are set to go
收费已定
once we're out
of the harbor, sir.
一旦我们出去
港口的，先生。
Let's carry on then.
那我们继续吧。
(DRAMATIC CHORD PLAYS)
（戏剧性的和弦演奏）
(SOLDIERS SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
（士兵们含糊其辞）
(GEOFFREY EXHALES)
（杰弗里呼气）
(HEINRICH SPEAKING GERMAN)
（海因里希说德语）
MARJORIE:
Did you enjoy your gift?
玛乔丽：
你喜欢你的礼物吗？
HEINRICH: Mmm.
海因里希：嗯。
I think now it's time
我想现在是时候了
that the fox shows his den
to the vixen.
狐狸露出了他的巢穴
到狐狸精。
(TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES)
（紧张的音乐继续）
- (GUS GRUNTS)
- (GUN FIRES QUIETLY)
-（格斯咕噜声）
-（枪声安静）
(SOLDIER THUDS)
（士兵重击）
- (CHOKING)
- (GUS GRUNTS)
-（窒息）
-（格斯咕噜声）
- (SOLDIERS CHEERING, LAUGHING)
- (UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
-（士兵们欢呼、大笑）
-（欢快的音乐播放）
Heron, why are
the lights still on?
苍鹭，为什么
灯还亮着吗？
I lit the room with oil lamps,
我用油灯照亮房间，
so they wouldn't notice
when the power went out.
所以他们不会注意到
当停电时。
(PEOPLE CHEERING, LAUGHING)
（人们欢呼、大笑）
(LOCK CLICKS)
（锁定点击）
(SCREAMS)
（尖叫声）
- (SAILOR SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
- (ARROW SWOOSHING)
-（水手用德语喊叫）
- （箭头呼啸）
- (SAILOR SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
- (GUNSHOTS)
-（水手用德语喊叫）
-（枪声）
(GEOFFREY PANTING)
（杰弗里气喘吁吁）
(GRENADE CLATTERS)
（手榴弹碰撞声）
- (ALARM BLARING)
- (SAILORS CLAMORING)
-（警报声）
-（水手们大声叫嚷）
- (GUNSHOTS)
- (SAILORS SCREAM)
-（枪声）
-（水手们尖叫）
- Look out!
- (GUNSHOTS)
- 小心！
-（枪声）
(GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
（枪声安静）
- (SCREAMS)
- (SAILORS CLAMORING)
-（尖叫声）
-（水手们大声叫嚷）
(SAILOR YELLS)
（水手大喊）
- (GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
- (SOLDIER GROANS)
-（枪声安静）
-（士兵呻吟声）
Freddy, rig this 88,
弗雷迪，装备这 88，
then take the first tug
with Haysey.
然后进行第一次拖船
与海西。
- Gute nacht.
- Guten abend.
- 晚上。
- 古腾阿卜德。
(SOLDIER 1 GROANING)
（士兵 1 呻吟）
GUS: Guten abend.
GUS：Guten 异常结束。
- (GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
- (SOLDIER 2 SCREAMS)
-（枪声安静）
-（士兵 2 尖叫）
- (SPEAKS GERMAN)
- (BOTH GRUNTING)
- （说德语）
-（两人都咕哝着）
- (GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
- (SAILOR 1 SCREAMS)
-（枪声安静）
-（水手 1 尖叫声）
(CHOKING)
（窒息）
GUS: (IN ENGLISH)
Terribly sorry, old boy.
格斯：（英语）
非常抱歉，老男孩。
- Do you mind? I seem to...
- (KNIFE CLANGS)
- 你介意吗？我好像...
-（刀子叮当声）
- (CHOKES)
- ...have misplaced my knife.
-（扼流圈）
- ...我的刀放错地方了。
(GROANS)
（呻吟声）
(ALARM CONTINUES BLARING)
（警报继续响起）
(CHOKING)
（窒息）
(LASSEN GRUNTING)
（拉森咕噜声）
(SAILOR YELLING IN GERMAN)
（水手用德语大喊）
(GROANS)
（呻吟声）
- (GUNSHOTS)
- (ADEDAYO SCREAMS)
-（枪声）
-（阿德达约尖叫声）
(GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
（枪声安静）
- (SAILOR 1 SPEAKING GERMAN)
- (ADEDAYO YELLS)
-（水手 1 说德语）
-（阿德达约大喊）
(SAILOR 2 GRUNTING)
（水手 2 咕哝着）
- (SAILOR 3 YELLS)
- (SAILOR 4 GASPS)
-（水手 3 喊叫）
-（水手 4 喘息）
(SAILOR 5 SHOUTS
IN GERMAN, GROANS)
（水手 5 喊叫
德语，呻吟声）
(SAILOR 6 YELLS)
（水手 6 喊叫）
(GRUNTING)
（咕噜声）
(SAILOR 7 SHOUTS IN GERMAN)
（水手 7 用德语喊叫）
(CHOKES)
（扼流圈）
(TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES)
（紧张的音乐继续）
- (SAILOR SPEAKS GERMAN)
- (GUN FIRES QUIETLY)
-（水手说德语）
-（枪声安静）
- (CLAMORING IN GERMAN)
- (GUN FIRES QUIETLY)
-（用德语叫嚷）
-（枪声安静）
(SAILOR 1 GRUNTS)
（水手 1 咕噜声）
(SAILOR 2 YELLING)
（水手 2 喊叫）
- (SAILOR 3 SCREAMING)
- (SLASHING)
-（水手 3 尖叫）
-（猛击）
- (SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
- (GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
-（用德语大喊）
-（枪声安静）
- (GUNSHOT)
- Bugger!
-（枪声）
- 混蛋！
(CLAMORING)
（吵闹）
Thank you, Billy.
谢谢你，比利。
(BOTH SHOUTING)
（两人都喊叫）
(SAILORS SPEAKING GERMAN)
（水手们讲德语）
- Oh!
- (LASSEN GRUNTS)
- 哦！
-（拉森咕哝）
(SAILOR 1 SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
（水手 1 用德语喊叫）
(SCREAMING, GASPING)
（尖叫，喘气）
(SAILOR 2 YELLING)
（水手 2 喊叫）
(SAILOR 3 ROARS)
（水手 3 咆哮）
(GASPING)
（喘气）
- (THUDS)
- (PANTING)
-（重击声）
-（气喘吁吁）
(FAINT CLAMORING)
（微弱的叫喊声）
(KNIFE CLANGS)
（刀子叮当作响）
(TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES)
（紧张的音乐继续）
(BOTH GRUNTING)
（两人都咕哝着）
(ADEDAYO YELLS, GRUNTS)
（阿德达约大喊，咕哝）
(GRUNTING, YELLING)
（咕哝，大喊）
(MUSIC FADES)
（音乐渐弱）
(DOOR CLICKS)
（敲门声）
I hope that's
not your blood, Lassen.
我希望那是
不是你的血，拉森。
I hope so too.
我也这样希望。
(SOLDIERS CLAMORING IN GERMAN)
（士兵们用德语喊叫）
- (GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
- (SAILORS GROAN, THUD)
-（枪声安静）
-（水手们呻吟，重重）
(MAN GRUNTS)
（男人咕哝）
Okay, boys, cast off.
好吧，孩子们，放弃吧。
Let's get this ship out of here.
我们让这艘船离开这里吧。
(GUS SIGHS)
（格斯叹气）
(IN ENGLISH) Go on. Go on...
（英语）继续。继续...
Go on!
继续！
LASSEN: There's three
more rooms just like this one.
拉森：有三个
还有更多像这个这样的房间。
That should stop the U-boats
for the next six months.
这应该能阻止U型潜艇
在接下来的六个月里。
Let's get this thing
towed out of here.
让我们得到这个东西
被拖离这里。
NDULUE: We are here, boys.
NDULUE：我们在这里，孩子们。
Quietly. Let's set a warning.
悄悄。让我们设置一个警告。
I need you to go
to the front of the boat
我需要你走
到船的前面
and attach the Vulcan
to the Duchessa,
并连接Vulcan
致公爵夫人，
Lassen and I
will head to the bridge.
拉森和我
将前往桥。
Okay. (SPEAKING YORUBA)
好的。 （约鲁巴语）
(IN ENGLISH)
Take the right side.
（用英语讲）
走右边。
And you, get up there
and get this thing started.
还有你，站起来
并开始这件事。
It's Gus.
是格斯。
GEOFFREY: Everyone's in place.
杰弗里：大家都就位了。
What,
什么，
you didn't actually think
it would work, did you?
你实际上并没有想到
它会起作用，是吗？
It was your plan.
这是你的计划。
Well, let's make sure
好吧，让我们确定一下
we keep our end of the bargain.
我们信守诺言。
Signal back and I'll heave off.
回信号，我就出发。
So, what happens now?
那么，现在会发生什么？
We wait for
the anchor chain to blow.
我们等待
锚链被吹。
When do
we expect that to happen?
什么时候
我们预计会发生这种情况吗？
- (MOTOR WHIRRING)
- Shortly, I hope.
-（电机呼呼声）
- 很快，我希望。
And then we're free to take her.
然后我们就可以带她去了。
However, the real race begins
once the fuel depot goes.
然而真正的比赛才开始
一旦燃料库消失。
Then we'll have every soldier
on the island turning up.
然后我们将拥有每一个士兵
在岛上出现。
We don't wanna
be around to witness that.
我们不想
见证这一点。
How long was that fuse
那个保险丝有多长
you attached
to the anchor chain?
你附加了
到锚链？
We'll find out soon enough.
我们很快就会知道。
(ALARM BLARING FAINTLY)
（警报声微弱）
ADEDAYO: Wait for it,
you're gonna catch the rope.
阿德达约：等等，
你会抓住绳子的。
(MEN CLAMORING IN YORUBA)
（约鲁巴语中男人的叫嚣）
(GRUNTING)
（咕噜声）
(DRAMATIC CHORD PLAYS)
（戏剧性的和弦演奏）
(IN ENGLISH) Come on.
（英语）来吧。
(WHIRS, CLICKS)
（呼呼声、卡哒声）
- (FAINT EXPLOSION)
- (PEOPLE GASP)
-（微弱的爆炸声）
-（人们倒吸一口凉气）
(CLAMORING)
（吵闹）
(LOCK RATTLING)
（锁发出嘎嘎声）
(BAND PLAYING SWING MUSIC)
（乐队演奏摇摆乐）
First domino falls.
第一张多米诺骨牌倒下。
- Hitch up the other line.
- Yes, boss.
- 搭上另一条线。
- 是的，老板。
Pick up the slack.
收拾残局。
FREDDY: They need to move her
before the fuel dump blows.
弗雷迪：他们需要移动她
在燃油堆爆炸之前。
Heron, we need Marjorie.
海伦，我们需要玛乔丽。
Leave Marjorie to me.
把玛乔丽交给我吧。
We'll catch you up.
我们会追上你的。
Very good.
非常好。
Let's go!
我们走吧！
(MUSIC FADES)
（音乐渐弱）
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
（悬疑的音乐播放）
HEINRICH:
I have to say, Fraulein,
海因里希：
我不得不说，小姐，
you were good.
你很好。
And you were sly.
而你很狡猾。
There are only
two types of people
只有
两种人
that are as sly as the fox.
像狐狸一样狡猾。
The German
德国人
and the Jew.
还有犹太人。
And you are not German.
而且你不是德国人。
I think now it's time...
我想现在是时候了...
(MUSIC BUILDS)
（音乐构建）
- ...for a real party.
- (LIGHTER CLICKS)
- ...真正的聚会。
-（轻击声）
(MUSIC FADES)
（音乐渐弱）
That wasn't
supposed to happen yet.
那不是
应该会发生。
- (FAINT EXPLOSIONS)
- (CHAINS RATTLING)
-（微弱的爆炸声）
-（链条嘎嘎作响）
Shackle her!
束缚她！
And follow me.
并跟随我。
(SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
（含糊不清地喊叫）
The harbor is under attack!
港口遭到攻击！
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
（讲西班牙语）
(ALL CLAMORING)
（所有人都在叫嚷）
(INTENSE WESTERN MUSIC PLAYING)
（激烈的西部音乐演奏）
(BINEA IN GERMAN)
（BINEA 德语）
(CLAMORING)
（吵闹）
(ALARM WAILING)
（警报声）
(FAINT SHOUTING)
（微弱的喊叫）
GUS: They're coming.
格斯：他们来了。
We need power on the engine.
我们需要为发动机提供动力。
(ENGINE ACCELERATING)
（发动机加速）
- She's too heavy!
- Pick up the slack!
-她太重了！
- 收拾残局！
(GRUNTS)
（咕噜声）
(SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
（用德语喊叫）
(COCKS GUN)
（旋塞枪）
GUS: (IN ENGLISH) Wait...
GUS：（用英语）等等……
(SOLDIER 1 IN GERMAN)
（德语：士兵 1）
(SOLDIER 2 SHOUTING
INDISTINCTLY)
（士兵 2 喊叫
模糊不清）
FREDDY: (IN ENGLISH)
She's not moving!
弗雷迪：（英语）
她没动！
SOLDIER 3: Fire! Fire! Fire!
士兵3：开火！火！火！
GUS: Wait for it.
格斯：等等。
(GUNSHOTS)
（枪声）
(CLAMORING)
（吵闹）
- (GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
- (GASPS)
-（枪声安静）
-（喘气）
(SOLDIERS SCREAMING)
（士兵们尖叫）
(SOLDIER 4 SHOUTS INDISTINCTLY)
（士兵 4 含糊不清地喊道）
(SOLDIER 5 YELLS)
（士兵 5 喊叫）
We need
more power on the engine.
我们需要
为发动机提供更多动力。
Give me more power! More power!
给我更多的力量！更多力量！
(ENGINE ACCELERATES HARDER)
（发动机加速更猛烈）
That's it, it's working!
就是这样，它正在工作！
- (ENGINE PULSES)
- That's it!
-（发动机脉冲）
- 就是这样！
(ADVENTUROUS
WESTERN MUSIC PLAYING)
（冒险的
西洋音乐演奏）
(OFFICER IN GERMAN)
（官员用德语）
- (CLAMORING CONTINUES)
- (GUNSHOTS)
-（叫嚷声仍在继续）
-（枪声）
(YELLING)
（大喊）
(SOLDIER SCREAMING)
（士兵尖叫）
NDULUE: (IN ENGLISH) Ready!
NDULUE：（英语）准备好了！
(MACHINE GUN FIRING)
（机枪射击）
(SOLDIERS SCREAMING)
（士兵们尖叫）
- (BOTH GRUNTING)
- (GUN FIRES)
-（两人都咕哝着）
-（枪声）
(SOLDIER SCREAMING)
（士兵尖叫）
(SCREAMS)
（尖叫声）
- (MOUTHING) Haysey!
- (TENSE MUSIC BUILDING)
-（口型）海西！
-（紧张的音乐楼）
- (EXPLOSION)
- (SCREAM)
-（爆炸）
-（尖叫）
(SOLDIERS CLAMORING)
（士兵们大声叫喊）
(OFFICER IN GERMAN)
（官员用德语）
(MUSIC SLOWS)
（音乐放慢）
(FAINT CLAMORING)
（微弱的叫喊声）
(IN ENGLISH)
We're out of range now.
（用英语讲）
我们现在已经超出范围了。
- I'm no expert.
- (HENRY GROANING)
- 我不是专家。
-（亨利呻吟）
But you've got a big old hole
in your shoulder, Haysey.
但你有一个大洞
在你的肩膀上，海西。
(SOLDIERS SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
（士兵们含糊地喊叫）
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
（德语）
- (GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
- (SOLDIERS GROAN)
-（枪声安静）
-（士兵们呻吟）
(SOLDIERS CLAMORING)
（士兵们大声叫喊）
(OFFICER SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
（警官用德语喊叫）
(SOLDIERS SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
（士兵们含糊地喊叫）
(OFFICER IN SPANISH)
（官员用西班牙语）
(IN ENGLISH) Captain,
（英语）船长，
would you explain to me
what's going on here?
你能向我解释一下吗
这里发生了什么？
The power is gone.
电源没了。
The fuel depot
has been sabotaged.
燃料库
已被破坏。
And no one knows
what's happening.
并且没有人知道
发生了什么。
But this is your fault.
但这是你的错。
Where is my ship?
我的船在哪里？
The Duchessa, where did it go?
公爵夫人，它去了哪里？
Someone's taken him
while you weren't looking.
有人带走了他
当你不看的时候。
You idiot!
你个傻冒！
You always have to say something
你总是必须说些什么
at the very wrong time.
在非常错误的时间。
There is never
a right time with you!
从来没有
和你一起度过一个合适的时光！
Your greed and perversion
你的贪婪和变态
has distracted you
from your duties.
分散了你的注意力
来自你的职责。
Now my harbor is destroyed.
现在我的港口被毁了。
And my ship is gone!
我的船也不见了！
And now you're gone too.
Thank you.
而现在你也走了。
谢谢。
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
（德语）
(EXPLOSION)
（爆炸）
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYS)
（紧张的音乐响起）
(IN ENGLISH) Impressive.
（英语）令人印象深刻。
HENRY: Sounds like
your detonators worked.
亨利：听起来像
你的雷管起作用了。
(BOTH LAUGHING)
（两人都笑）
(SIGHS)
（叹气）
(FAINT CLAMORING)
（微弱的叫喊声）
(TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES)
（紧张的音乐继续）
(OFFICER SPEAKS GERMAN)
（军官说德语）
(SOLDIERS SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
（士兵们含糊地喊叫）
(MUSIC FADES OUT)
（音乐淡出）
Chapeau, mademoiselle.
起首，小姐。
(IN ENGLISH) You play well.
You really are the vixen.
（英语）你打得很好。
你果然是狐狸精啊。
Am I?
我是吗？
Well, my hand's been revealed.
嗯，我的手已经露出来了。
So, what now?
所以现在怎么办？
Now, I possess your hand
现在，我握着你的手
and for everything
you have done to me,
和对于一切
你对我所做的事，
I will visit
a thousand fold upon you.
我会参观
千倍地压在你身上。
(IN GERMAN)
（在德国）
(CHAINS CLANG)
（铁链叮当作响）
(IN ENGLISH) Yeah.
（英语）是的。
(COCKS GUN)
（旋塞枪）
But no.
但不是。
- (SOLDIER SHOUTS)
- (GUN FIRING QUIETLY)
-（士兵喊叫）
-（枪声安静）
- (DOOR OPENS)
- Lie down.
-（门打开）
- 躺。
Gus, we can't wait much longer.
格斯，我们不能等太久了。
They're coming.
他们来了。
If we stay here,
如果我们留在这里，
we'll lose contact
with the others.
我们会失去联系
与其他人。
Hold fast, Billy.
坚持住，比利。
Heron has a way of surviving
and Marjorie,
苍鹭有一种生存之道
还有玛乔丽，
well... good luck with that.
好吧...祝你好运。
That's a patrol boat
coming towards us.
这是一艘巡逻艇
向我们走来。
- Gus, we need to leave. Now.
- (COCKS GUN)
- 格斯，我们需要离开。现在。
- (旋塞枪)
Hold on...
坚持，稍等...
(BOAT APPROACHING)
（船靠近）
It's them.
是他们。
KAMP BILLY: RH.
坎普·比利： RH。
- KB.
- GUS: Marjorie.
- KB。
- GUS：玛乔丽。
Overdressed and underdressed
at the same time.
穿得太过分和穿得太过分
同时。
Come on, let's get you
out of those shackles.
来吧，让我们来接你
摆脱那些束缚。
(STATIC CRACKLING)
（静电爆裂声）
Come in, Violet.
进来吧，紫罗兰。
Calling H.M.S. Violet.
呼叫紫罗兰号战列舰。
Come in, Violet.
进来，紫罗兰。
GEOFFREY: (ON RADIO)
This is Maid Honor.
杰弗里：（广播）
这是女仆荣誉。
Go ahead, Maid Honor.
来吧，女仆荣誉。
- Loudspeaker.
- (CLICKS)
- 扬声器。
-（点击）
GEOFFREY: Sorry to bother you
at this time of the night,
杰弗里：很抱歉打扰您
在深夜的这个时候，
but we've found ourselves
with one or two items
但我们发现自己
与一两个项目
that might be
of interest to you.
那可能是
您感兴趣。
Shall we rendezvous
for a handover?
我们可以见面吗
交接？
Get me Admiral Pound.
给我庞德上将。
(TENSE ADVENTUROUS
MUSIC PLAYING)
（紧张的冒险
音乐播放）
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
（电话铃声）
- Yes?
- GUBBINS: (OH PHONE) Sir,
- 是的？
- 古宾斯：（电话）先生，
- good news and bad news.
- Yes, yes. Get to it.
- 好消息和坏消息。
- 是的是的。开始吧。
Bad news, they didn't sink her.
坏消息，他们没有击沉她。
Good news,
好消息，
they stole her.
他们偷走了她。
Congratulations, Prime Minister.
恭喜你，首相。
(TENSE ADVENTUROUS
MUSIC CONTINUES)
（紧张的冒险
音乐继续）
(MUSIC FADES OUT)
（音乐淡出）
(MEN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
（男人们含糊不清地喊叫）
OFFICER: Hold it there!
官员： 拿着它！
Commander.
指挥官。
You were ordered
by Admiral Pound
你被命令了
作者：庞德海军上将
to cease activities.
停止活动。
You did not.
你没有。
Therefore, you are
to be returned to England
因此，你是
将返回英国
to face a tribunal. You.
面对法庭。你。
Return to your tug
with the rest of your militia.
返回您的拖船
和你的其他民兵一起。
- Take them to the brig.
- OFFICER: Sir!
- 带他们去双桅船。
- 军官：先生！
Good to see you too, Commander.
我也很高兴见到你，指挥官。
Separate cells.
分离细胞。
OFFICER: Follow me!
官员：跟我来！
Let's go! Let's get moving!
我们走吧！让我们行动起来吧！
- RH.
- KB.
- 右手。
- KB。
SAILOR: Come on.
水手：来吧。
Go on, move.
继续，移动。
One moment, seaman.
等一下，海员。
(CURIOUS WESTERN MUSIC PLAYING)
（好奇的西方音乐演奏）
Billy.
比利.
One eye on the boundary...
一只眼睛盯着边界……
One eye on the pub.
一只眼睛盯着酒吧。
They'll thank you
for this one day.
他们会感谢你的
为了这一天。
I'm not sure
我不知道
that's what we were
really looking for, was it,
我们就是这样
真的在寻找，是吗，
Your Highness?
殿下？
Shop's open
for you anytime, Major.
商店开门了
随时为您服务，少校。
GLORIA: Sorry to intrude,
Prime Minister,
格洛丽亚：抱歉打扰，
总理，
but M thought
you should see this.
但M认为
你应该看到这个。
CHURCHILL: Thank you, Gloria.
丘吉尔：谢谢你，格洛丽亚。
(MUSIC TURNS HAPPY)
（音乐变得快乐）
(MAN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
（男子含糊不清地喊叫）
- (GATE RATTLING)
- GUARD: Line up. Face front!
-（门嘎嘎作响）
- 警卫：排队。正面！
Line up. Face front!
排队。正面！
No need to shout.
无需喊叫。
GUARD: Stand still!
警卫：站住！
Any chance of a cup of tea?
有机会喝杯茶吗？
You, back up to the wall.
你，背靠墙吧。
Off the cloth, moth.
掉布，飞蛾。
GUARD: Stand straight!
警卫：站直！
(DOOR OPENS)
（门打开）
- (FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
- (WALKING STICK CLACKING)
-（脚步声接近）
-（手杖卡哒作响）
CHURCHILL: Never before
have the senior Military
丘吉尔：以前从未有过
拥有高级军事
and Navy Commanders
of this country
和海军指挥官
这个国家的
been so united
in their condemnation.
如此团结
在他们的谴责中。
It is their view
这是他们的观点
that the discipline
纪律
on which
our armed forces depends
其上
我们的武装部队取决于
has been undermined
by men serving no master
已被破坏
不为主人服务的人
but their own thirst
for blood, murder and mayhem.
但他们自己的渴求
流血、谋杀和混乱。
Men who disobeyed a direct order
不服从直接命令的人
from the Admiral
of the fleet himself,
来自海军上将
舰队本身，
and chose instead
并选择了
to trust the whim and intuition
相信突发奇想和直觉
of the man standing beside him.
站在他身边的那个男人。
How dare they.
他们怎么敢。
When only this morning,
就在今天早上，
the first American soldiers
arrived on British soil,
第一批美国士兵
抵达英国土地，
ready to stand
shoulder to shoulder
准备站立
并肩
with us in Europe.
和我们一起在欧洲。
Allies who risked death
crossing the North Atlantic,
冒着死亡危险的盟友
横渡北大西洋，
and only by some miracle
只有奇迹
found their crossing
untroubled by Nazi U-boats.
找到了他们的十字路口
不受纳粹潜艇的困扰。
A happy circumstance,
I might add,
幸福的境遇，
我可能会补充一点，
which cannot be accounted for,
无法解释的，
but which has cleared the way
for the United States
但这已经扫清了道路
对于美国
to enter the European war.
进入欧洲战争。
And for which I know
我知道为此
President Roosevelt
to be immeasurably grateful.
罗斯福总统
表示无限的感激。
But setting aside
但抛开
this stroke
of unexplained fortune,
这一划
无法解释的财富，
what is to be done
with this unruly company
什么是要做
和这个不守规矩的公司
who do not obey orders?
谁不服从命令？
Who seem to have formed
谁似乎已经形成
their own ministry
of ungentlemanly warfare.
他们自己的事工
不绅士的战争。
(CURIOUS WESTERN MUSIC PLAYING)
（好奇的西方音乐演奏）
From now on, they work for me.
从现在开始，他们为我工作。
(MUSIC TURNS WHIMSICAL)
（音乐变得异想天开）
(MUSIC FADES OUT)
（音乐淡出）
(CAPTIVATING MUSIC PLAYING)
（迷人的音乐播放）
(AMUSING WESTERN MUSIC PLAYING)
（有趣的西方音乐演奏）
(MUSIC FADES OUT)
（音乐淡出）
(EXCITING MUSIC PLAYING)
（激动人心的音乐演奏）
(EXCITING MUSIC CONTINUES)
（激动人心的音乐继续）
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
（紧张的音乐播放）
(CURIOUS GENTLE MUSIC PLAYING)
（播放着好奇的轻柔音乐）
(MUSIC FADES OUT)
（音乐淡出）